<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<Movies version="1.1">
  <!--Projeto 06 - Banco de Dados - Viludani-->
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0068646/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Godfather</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>24 March 1972 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Francis Ford Coppola</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Godfather is a 1972 American crime film directed by Francis Ford Coppola and produced by Albert S. Ruddy, based on Mario Puzo's best-selling novel of the same name. It stars Marlon Brando and Al Pacino as the leaders of a fictional New York crime family. The story, spanning 1945 to 1955, chronicles the family under the patriarch Vito Corleone (Brando), focusing on the transformation of Michael Corleone (Pacino) from reluctant family outsider to ruthless mafia boss.
Paramount Pictures obtained the rights to the novel for the price of $80,000, before it gained popularity. Studio executives had trouble finding a director; their first few candidates turned down the position. They and Coppola disagreed over who would play several characters, in particular, Vito and Michael. Filming took place on location, primarily around New York and in Sicily, and was completed ahead of schedule. The musical score was principally composed by Nino Rota, with additional pieces by Carmine Coppola.
The film was the highest-grossing film of 1972 and was for a time the highest-grossing film ever made. It won the Oscars for Best Picture, Best Actor (Brando) and Best Adapted Screenplay (for Puzo and Coppola). Its seven other Oscar nominations included Pacino, James Caan, Robert Duvall (Best Supporting Actor), and Coppola for Best Director.
The Godfather is widely regarded as one of the greatest films in world cinema and one of the most influential, especially in the gangster genre. It was selected for preservation in the U.S. National Film Registry of the Library of Congress in 1990, being deemed &quot;culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant&quot; and is ranked the second-greatest film in American cinema (behind Citizen Kane) by the American Film Institute. It was followed by sequels The Godfather Part II (1974) and The Godfather Part III (1990).</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Godfather</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110912/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Pulp Fiction</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>14 October 1994 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Quentin Tarantino</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Pulp Fiction is a 1994 American crime film written and directed by Quentin Tarantino; it is based on a story by Tarantino and Roger Avary. Starring John Travolta, Samuel L. Jackson, Bruce Willis, Ving Rhames, and Uma Thurman, it tells several stories of criminal Los Angeles. The film's title refers to the pulp magazines and hardboiled crime novels popular during the mid-20th century, known for their graphic violence and punchy dialogue.
Tarantino wrote Pulp Fiction in 1992 and 1993, incorporating scenes that Avary originally wrote for True Romance (1993). Its plot occurs out of chronological order. The film is also self-referential from its opening moments, beginning with a title card that gives two dictionary definitions of &quot;pulp&quot;. Considerable screen time is devoted to monologues and casual conversations with eclectic dialogue revealing each character's perspectives on several subjects, and the film features an ironic combination of humor and strong violence. TriStar Pictures reportedly turned down the script as &quot;too demented&quot;. Miramax co-chairman Harvey Weinstein was enthralled, however, and the film became the first that Miramax fully financed.
Pulp Fiction won the Palme d'Or at the 1994 Cannes Film Festival, and was a major critical and commercial success. It was nominated for seven Oscars, including Best Picture, and won Best Original Screenplay; it earned Travolta, Jackson, and Thurman Academy Award nominations and revitalized and/or elevated their careers. Its development, marketing, distribution, and profitability had a sweeping effect on independent cinema.
Pulp Fiction has been widely regarded as Tarantino's masterpiece, with particular praise for its screenwriting. The self-reflexivity, unconventional structure, and extensive homage and pastiche have led critics to describe it as a touchstone of postmodern film. It is often considered a cultural watershed, influencing movies and other media that adopted elements of its style. In 2008, Entertainment Weekly named it the best film since 1983 and it has appeared on many critics' lists of the greatest films ever made. In 2013, Pulp Fiction was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as &quot;culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant&quot;.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pulp_Fiction</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0167260/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>17 December 2003 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Peter Jackson</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King is a 2003 fantasy adventure film co-produced, co-written, and directed by Peter Jackson based on the second and third volumes of J. R. R. Tolkien's The Lord of the Rings. It is the third and final instalment  in The Lord of the Rings trilogy, following The Fellowship of the Ring (2001) and The Two Towers (2002), preceding The Hobbit film trilogy (2012–14).
Released on 17 December 2003, The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King became one of the most critically and commercially successful films of all time. It was the second film to gross $1 billion worldwide ($1.12 billion), becoming the highest-grossing film released by New Line Cinema, as well as the biggest financial success for Time Warner in general at the time. The film was the highest-grossing film of 2003 and, by the end of its theatrical run, the second highest-grossing film in history. As of August 2018, it is the 21st highest-grossing film of all time.
At the 76th Academy Awards, it won all 11 Academy Awards for which it was nominated, therefore holding the record for highest Oscar sweep. The wins included the awards for Best Picture, the first time a fantasy film had done so; it was also the second sequel to win Oscars for Best Picture and Best Director (following The Godfather Part II). The film jointly holds the record for the largest number of Academy Awards won with Ben-Hur (1959) and Titanic (1997). The film has been re-released three times first in 2011 and then 2017, as well as 2018.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lord_of_the_Rings:_The_Return_of_the_King</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0211915/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Amélie</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Comedy</value>
      <value>Romance</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>8 February 2002 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Jean-Pierre Jeunet</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Amélie (also known as Le Fabuleux Destin d'Amélie Poulain; French pronunciation: ​[lə fa.by.lø des.tɛ̃ d‿a.me.li puˈlɛ̃]; English: The Fabulous Destiny of Amélie Poulain) is a 2001 French romantic comedy film directed by Jean-Pierre Jeunet. Written by Jeunet with Guillaume Laurant, the film is a whimsical depiction of contemporary Parisian life, set in Montmartre. It tells the story of a shy waitress, played by Audrey Tautou, who decides to change the lives of those around her for the better, while struggling with her own isolation. The film was a co-production between companies in France and Germany. Taking in over $33 million in a limited theatrical release, it is to date the highest-grossing French-language film released in the United States, and one of the biggest international successes for a French movie.The film received critical acclaim and was a major box office success. Amélie won Best Film at the European Film Awards; it also won four César Awards in 2002 (including Best Film and Best Director), two BAFTA Awards (including Best Original Screenplay), and was nominated for five Academy Awards.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Am%C3%A9lie</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0062622/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>2001: A Space Odyssey</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>4 July 1968 (Brazil)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Stanley Kubrick</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>2001: A Space Odyssey is a 1968 epic science fiction film produced and directed by Stanley Kubrick. The screenplay was written by Kubrick and Arthur C. Clarke, and was inspired by Clarke's short story &quot;The Sentinel&quot;. A novel also called 2001: A Space Odyssey, written concurrently with the screenplay, was published soon after the film was released. The film, which follows a voyage to Jupiter with the sentient computer HAL after the discovery of a mysterious black monolith affecting human evolution, deals with themes of existentialism, human evolution, technology, artificial intelligence, and the possibility of extraterrestrial life. The film is noted for its scientifically accurate depiction of spaceflight, pioneering special effects, and ambiguous imagery. Sound and dialogue are used sparingly and often in place of traditional cinematic and narrative techniques. The soundtrack incorporates a number of pieces of classical music, among them Also sprach Zarathustra by Richard Strauss, The Blue Danube by Johann Strauss II, and works by Aram Khachaturian and György Ligeti.
2001: A Space Odyssey was financed and distributed by American studio Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, but filmed and edited almost entirely in England, where Kubrick lived, using the facilities of MGM-British Studios and Shepperton Studios. Production was subcontracted to Kubrick's production company, and care was taken that the film would be sufficiently &quot;British&quot; to qualify for the Eady Levy, a UK tax on box-office receipts. The film received mixed reactions from critics and audiences upon its release, but garnered a cult following and became the highest-grossing North American film of 1968. It was nominated for four Academy Awards; Kubrick received one for his direction of visual effects. A sequel, 2010: The Year We Make Contact, directed by Peter Hyams, was released in 1984.
2001: A Space Odyssey is widely regarded as one of the greatest and most influential films ever made. In 1991, it was deemed &quot;culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant&quot; by the United States Library of Congress and selected for preservation in the National Film Registry. Sight &amp; Sound magazine ranked 2001: A Space Odyssey sixth in the top ten films of all time in its 2002 and 2012 critics' polls editions; it also tied for second place in the magazine's 2012 directors' poll. In 2010, it was named the greatest film of all time by The Moving Arts Film Journal.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2001:_A_Space_Odyssey_(film)</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0434409/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>V for Vendetta</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>17 March 2006 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>James McTeigue</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>V for Vendetta is a British graphic novel written by Alan Moore and illustrated by David Lloyd (with additional art by Tony Weare). Initially published in black and white as an ongoing serial in the short-lived UK anthology Warrior, it morphed into a ten-issue limited series published by DC Comics. Subsequent collected editions have been typically published under DC's more specialized imprint Vertigo. The story depicts a dystopian and post-apocalyptic near-future history version of the United Kingdom in the 1990s, preceded by a nuclear war in the 1980s which had devastated most of the rest of the world. The Nordic supremacist and neo-fascist Norsefire political party has exterminated its opponents in concentration camps and rules the country as a police state.
The comics follow its title character and protagonist, V, an anarchist revolutionary dressed in a Guy Fawkes mask, as he begins an elaborate and theatrical revolutionist campaign to kill his former captors, bring down the fascist state and convince the people to abandon democracy in favour of anarchy, while inspiring a young woman, Evey Hammond, to be his protégé.
DC Comics had sold more than 500,000 copies of the books in the United States as of 2006. Warner Bros. released a film adaptation of the same title in 2005.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V_for_Vendetta</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0246578/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Donnie Darko</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>26 October 2001 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Richard Kelly</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Donnie Darko is a 2001 science fiction film written and directed by Richard Kelly. It stars Jake Gyllenhaal, Jena Malone, Drew Barrymore, Mary McDonnell, Katharine Ross, Patrick Swayze, Noah Wyle, and Maggie Gyllenhaal. The film follows the adventures of the troubled title character as he seeks the meaning behind his doomsday-related visions.
Filmed over the course of 28 days (coincidentally mirroring the time transpired in the movie), the film was almost released straight-to-video. Donnie Darko was screened at the Sundance Film Festival on January 19, 2001, before receiving a limited theatrical release on October 26, 2001 by Flower Films. Due to the film's advertising featuring a crashing plane and the September 11 attacks that transpired a month before, the film was scarcely advertised. In the end, Donnie Darko grossed just over $7.5 million worldwide on a budget of $4.5 million. Despite its lackluster box office performance, Donnie Darko received critical acclaim. Critics lauded the film's story, acting, and tone. The film was listed #2 in Empire's 50 Greatest Independent Films of All Time, as well as #63 in Empire's 500 Greatest Movies of All Time.It was released on VHS and DVD in March 2002. The film became a surprising success on the home video market, reportedly grossing over $10 million in home video sales. The film has also developed a cult following. The film's soundtrack is also famous for its cover of Tears for Fears's &quot;Mad World&quot; by Gary Jules and Michael Andrews. The cover reached number one on the UK Singles Chart and stayed there for three consecutive weeks. The song also achieved lukewarm success in the United States, reaching number 30 on the Billboard Modern Rock Tracks chart. A director's cut was released in 2004, on a two-disc special edition DVD. A stage adaptation appeared in 2007, and a sequel, S. Darko, in 2009.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donnie_Darko</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0075148/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Rocky</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Sport</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>3 December 1976 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>John G. Avildsen</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Rocky is a 1976 American sports drama film directed by John G. Avildsen and both written by and starring Sylvester Stallone. It tells the rags to riches American Dream story of Rocky Balboa, an uneducated but kind-hearted working class Italian-American boxer working as a debt collector for a loan shark in the slums of Philadelphia.  Rocky, a small-time club fighter, gets a shot at the world heavyweight championship. The film also stars Talia Shire as Adrian, Burt Young as Adrian's brother Paulie, Burgess Meredith as Rocky's trainer Mickey Goldmill, and Carl Weathers as the champion, Apollo Creed.
The film, made on a budget of just over $1 million, was a sleeper hit; it earned $225 million in global box office receipts, becoming the highest-grossing film of 1976, and went on to win three Oscars, including Best Picture. The film received many positive reviews and turned Stallone into a major star. In 2006, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being &quot;culturally, historically or aesthetically significant&quot;. Rocky is considered to be one of the greatest sports films ever made and was ranked as the second-best in the genre, after Raging Bull, by the American Film Institute in 2008.
The film has spawned six sequels: Rocky II (1979), Rocky III (1982), Rocky IV (1985), Rocky V (1990), Rocky Balboa (2006) and Creed (2015). Stallone portrays Rocky in all six sequels, wrote the first five, and directed four (Avildsen returned to direct Rocky V and Ryan Coogler directed Creed). An eighth film and direct sequel to Creed, titled Creed II, is scheduled for release in 2018 with Steven Caple Jr. directing and Stallone returning to star and write the script.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rocky</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0435761/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Toy Story 3</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Comedy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>18 June 2010 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Lee Unkrich</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Toy Story 3 is a  2010 American 3D computer-animated comedy-drama film produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures. It is the third installment in Pixar's Toy Story series, and the sequel to 1999's Toy Story 2. It was directed by Lee Unkrich, the editor of the first two films and the co-director of Toy Story 2, written by Michael Arndt, while Unkrich wrote the story along with John Lasseter and Andrew Stanton, respectively director and co-writer of the first two films. 
In the film's ensemble voice cast, Tom Hanks, Tim Allen, Don Rickles, John Ratzenberger, Wallace Shawn, R. Lee Ermey, John Morris and Laurie Metcalf reprise their roles from the first two films with Joan Cusack, Estelle Harris and Jodi Benson who reprise their Toy Story 2 roles of Jessie, Mrs. Potato Head and Barbie, respectively. Jim Varney, who voiced Slinky Dog in the first two films, died 10 years before the release of the third film, so the role of Slinky was passed down to Blake Clark. They are joined by Ned Beatty, Michael Keaton, Whoopi Goldberg, Timothy Dalton, Kristen Schaal, Bonnie Hunt, and Jeff Garlin who voice the new characters introduced in this film. The plot focuses on the toys Woody, Buzz Lightyear, and their friends accidentally being donated to a day care center as their owner, Andy, prepares to leave for college, and racing to get home before Andy leaves. This is the last Toy Story film featuring Don Rickles as Mr. Potato Head and R. Lee Ermey as Sarge since Rickles died in April 2017 and Ermey died in April 2018.
The film was released in theaters June 18, 2010, and played worldwide from June through October in the Disney Digital 3-D, RealD, and IMAX 3D formats. Toy Story 3 was the first film to be released theatrically with Dolby Surround 7.1 sound. Like its predecessors, Toy Story 3 received critical acclaim upon release, with critics praising the vocal performances, screenplay, emotional depth, animation, and Randy Newman's musical score.It became the second Pixar film (after Up) and third animated film overall (after Beauty and the Beast and Up) to receive an Academy Award nomination for Best Picture. The film received four more Academy Award nominations for Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Sound Editing, Best Animated Feature and Best Original Song, winning the latter two. Toy Story 3 grossed over $1 billion worldwide, becoming the highest-grossing film of 2010—both in North America and worldwide—and the fourth highest-grossing film at the time of its release, as well as the fourth highest-grossing animated film of all time, the first animated film to generate over $1 billion in ticket sales, and Pixar's second highest-grossing film to date, the first being Incredibles 2. A sequel, Toy Story 4, directed by Josh Cooley, is scheduled to be released on June 21, 2019.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toy_Story_3</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110357/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Lion King</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>24 June 1994 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Roger Allers</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Lion King is a 1994 American animated epic musical film produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation and released by Walt Disney Pictures. It is the 32nd Disney animated feature film, and the fifth animated film produced during a period known as the Disney Renaissance.  The Lion King was directed by Roger Allers and Rob Minkoff, produced by Don Hahn, and has a screenplay credited to Irene Mecchi, Jonathan Roberts, and Linda Woolverton. Its original songs were written by composer Elton John and lyricist Tim Rice, with a score by Hans Zimmer. The film features an ensemble voice cast that includes Matthew Broderick, James Earl Jones, Jeremy Irons, Jonathan Taylor Thomas, Moira Kelly, Nathan Lane, Ernie Sabella, Rowan Atkinson, Robert Guillaume, Madge Sinclair, Whoopi Goldberg, Cheech Marin, and Jim Cummings. The story takes place in a kingdom of lions in Africa and was influenced by William Shakespeare's Hamlet.
The Lion King tells the story of Simba, a young lion who is to succeed his father, Mufasa, as King of the Pride Lands; however, after Simba's uncle Scar (Mufasa's jealous younger brother), murders Mufasa, Simba is manipulated into thinking he was responsible and flees into exile. Upon maturation living with two wastrels, Simba is given some valuable perspective from his childhood friend, Nala, and his shaman, Rafiki, before returning to challenge Scar to end his tyranny and take his place in the Circle of Life as the rightful King.
Development of The Lion King began in 1988 during a meeting between Jeffrey Katzenberg, Roy E. Disney, and Peter Schneider while promoting Oliver &amp; Company in Europe. Thomas Disch wrote a film treatment, and Woolverton developed the first scripts while George Scribner was signed on as director, being later joined by Allers. Production began in 1991 concurrently with Pocahontas, which wound up attracting many of Disney's top animators. Some time after the staff traveled to Hell's Gate National Park in Kenya to research on the film's setting and animals, Scribner left production disagreeing with the decision to turn the film into a musical and was replaced by Minkoff. When Hahn joined the project, he was dissatisfied with the script and the story was promptly rewritten. Nearly 20 minutes of animation sequences were produced at Disney’s Hollywood Studios theme park in Florida. Computer animation was also used in several scenes, most notably in the wildebeest stampede sequence.
The Lion King was released on June 15, 1994, to a positive reaction from critics, who praised the film for its music, story, and animation. With a worldwide gross of $766 million, it finished its theatrical run as the highest-grossing release of 1994 and the second highest-grossing film of all time. It is also the highest-grossing traditionally animated film of all time. The Lion King garnered two Academy Awards for its achievement in music and the Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy. The film has led to many derived works, such as a Broadway adaptation; two direct-to-video follow-ups—the sequel, The Lion King II: Simba's Pride (1998), and the prequel/parallel, The Lion King 1½ (2004); two television series, Timon and Pumbaa and The Lion Guard; and a 3D re-release, in 2011.
In 2016, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being &quot;culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant&quot;. A CGI remake of the film directed by Jon Favreau is scheduled for a July 19, 2019 release in the United States.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lion_King</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0045152/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Singin' in the Rain</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Comedy</value>
      <value>Musical</value>
      <value>Romance</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>11 April 1952 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Stanley Donen</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Singin' in the Rain is a 1952 American musical-romantic comedy film directed and choreographed by Gene Kelly and Stanley Donen, starring Kelly, Donald O'Connor, and Debbie Reynolds. It offers a lighthearted depiction of Hollywood in the late 1920s, with the three stars portraying performers caught up in the transition from silent films to &quot;talkies&quot;.
The film was only a modest hit when first released. Donald O'Connor won the Golden Globe Award for Best Actor – Motion Picture Musical or Comedy, and Betty Comden and Adolph Green won the Writers Guild of America Award for their screenplay, while Jean Hagen was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress. However, it has since been accorded legendary status by contemporary critics, and is frequently regarded as the best film musical ever made, and the best film ever made in the &quot;Freed Unit&quot; at Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer. It topped the AFI's Greatest Movie Musicals list and is ranked as the fifth-greatest American motion picture of all time in its updated list of the greatest American films in 2007. In 1989, the United States Library of Congress selected the film for preservation in the National Film Registry. In 2005 the British Film Institute included it in their list of the 50 films you should see by the age of 14. In Sight &amp; Sound magazine's 2017 list of the 50 greatest films of all time, Singin' in the Rain placed 20th.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Singin%27_in_the_Rain</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0097576/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>24 May 1989 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Steven Spielberg</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade is a 1989 American action-adventure film directed by Steven Spielberg, from a story co-written by executive producer George Lucas. It is the third installment in the Indiana Jones franchise. Harrison Ford reprises the title role and Sean Connery plays Indiana's father, Henry Jones, Sr. Other cast members featured include Alison Doody, Denholm Elliott, Julian Glover, River Phoenix, and John Rhys-Davies. In the film, set largely in 1938, Indiana searches for his father, a Holy Grail scholar, who has been kidnapped by Nazis.
After the mixed reaction to Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom, Spielberg chose to tone down the gore in the next installment. During the five years between Temple of Doom and Last Crusade, he and executive producer Lucas reviewed several scripts before accepting Jeffrey Boam's. Filming locations included Spain, Italy, West Germany, Jordan, the United Kingdom, and the United States.The film was released in North America on May 24, 1989 to mostly positive reviews and a financial success, earning $474.2 million at the worldwide box office totals. It won an Academy Award for Best Sound Editing.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indiana_Jones_and_the_Last_Crusade</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0268978/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>A Beautiful Mind</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Biography</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>4 January 2002 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Ron Howard</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>A Beautiful Mind is a 2001 American biographical drama film based on the life of John Nash, a Nobel Laureate in Economics. The film was directed by Ron Howard, from a screenplay written by Akiva Goldsman. It was inspired by a bestselling, Pulitzer Prize-nominated 1998 book of the same name by Sylvia Nasar. The film stars Russell Crowe, along with Ed Harris, Jennifer Connelly, Paul Bettany, Adam Goldberg, Judd Hirsch, Josh Lucas, Anthony Rapp, and Christopher Plummer in supporting roles. The story begins in Nash's days as a graduate student at Princeton University. Early in the film, Nash begins to develop paranoid schizophrenia and endures delusional episodes while watching the burden his condition brings on wife Alicia and friends.
The film opened in the United States cinemas on December 21, 2001. It went on to gross over $313 million worldwide and won four Academy Awards, for Best Picture, Best Director, Best Adapted Screenplay and Best Supporting Actress. It was also nominated for Best Actor, Best Film Editing, Best Makeup and Best Original Score.It was well received by critics, but has been criticized for its inaccurate portrayal of some aspects of Nash's life, especially his other family and a son born out of wedlock, in addition to shying away from his bisexuality. However, the filmmakers have stated that the film was not meant to be a literal representation of Nash's life.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Beautiful_Mind_(film)</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0070047/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Exorcist</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Horror</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>26 December 1973 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>William Friedkin</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Exorcist is an American media franchise that originated with William Peter Blatty's 1971 horror novel of the same name and most prominently featured in a 1973 film adapted from the novel, and many subsequent prequels and sequels. All of these installments focus on fictional accounts of people possessed by Pazuzu, the main antagonist of the series, and the efforts of religious authorities to counter this possession.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Exorcist</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0338564/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Infernal Affairs</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Mystery</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>12 December 2002 (Hong Kong)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Wai-Keung Lau</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Infernal Affairs is a 2002 Hong Kong crime thriller film directed by Andrew Lau and Alan Mak and written by Mak and Felix Chong. It tells the story of a police officer who infiltrates a Triad, and another officer secretly working for the same gang. It is the first in the Infernal Affairs series and is followed by Infernal Affairs II and Infernal Affairs III.
The Chinese title means &quot;The Unceasing Path&quot;, a reference to Avici, the lowest level of Hell in Buddhism, where one endures suffering incessantly. The English title is a word play, combining the adjective 'infernal' (concerning hell) with internal affairs – the police department concerned with investigating its own officers.
The film had been selected as the Hong Kong entry for the Best Foreign Language Film at the 76th Academy Awards but was not nominated. Miramax Films acquired the United States distribution rights and gave it a limited US theatrical release in 2004. Martin Scorsese successfully remade the film in 2006 as The Departed, which won the Academy Award for Best Picture.  An Indian remake of the film is also in the works.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infernal_Affairs</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0382932/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Ratatouille</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Comedy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>29 June 2007 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Brad Bird</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Ratatouille (; French pronunciation: ​[ʁatatuj]), is a 2007 American computer-animated comedy film produced by Pixar and released by Buena Vista Pictures Distribution. It is the eighth film produced by Pixar and was co-written and directed by Brad Bird, who took over from Jan Pinkava in 2005. The title refers to a French dish, &quot;ratatouille&quot;, which is served at the end of the film and is also a play on words about the species of the main character. The film stars the voices of Patton Oswalt as Remy, an anthropomorphic rat who is interested in cooking; Lou Romano as Linguini, a young garbage boy who befriends Remy; Ian Holm as Skinner, the head chef of Auguste Gusteau's restaurant; Janeane Garofalo as Colette, a rôtisseur at Gusteau's restaurant; Peter O'Toole as Anton Ego, a restaurant critic; Brian Dennehy as Django, Remy's father and leader of his clan; Peter Sohn as Emile, Remy's older brother; and Brad Garrett as Auguste Gusteau, a recently deceased chef. The plot follows a rat named Remy, who dreams of becoming a chef and tries to achieve his goal by forming an alliance with a Parisian restaurant's garbage boy.
Development of Ratatouille began in 2000 when Pinkava wrote the original concepts of the film. In 2005, Bird was approached to direct the film and revise the story. Bird and some of the film's crew members also visited Paris for inspiration. To create the food animation used in the film, the crew consulted chefs from both France and the United States. Bird also interned at Thomas Keller's The French Laundry restaurant, where Keller developed the confit byaldi, a dish used in the film.
Ratatouille premiered on June 22, 2007, at the Kodak Theatre in Los Angeles, California, with its general release June 29, 2007, in the United States. The film grossed $620.7 million at the box office and received critical acclaim. The film won the Academy Award for Best Animated Feature, and was later voted one of the 100 greatest motion pictures of the 21st century by a 2016 poll of international critics conducted by BBC.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ratatouille_(film)</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107290/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Jurassic Park</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>11 June 1993 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Steven Spielberg</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Jurassic Park is an American science fiction media franchise centered on a disastrous attempt to create a theme park of de-exinct dinosaurs. The dinosaurs escape confinement and terrorize the human characters. It began in 1990 when Universal Pictures and Amblin Entertainment bought the rights to the novel by Michael Crichton before it was even published.
The book was successful, as was Steven Spielberg's 1993 film adaptation, which led to four sequels, although only the first two films were based on the novels. Numerous video games based on the franchise have been created by various software developers since the release of the 1993 film. Since 1996, several water rides based on the series have been opened at various Universal theme parks.
The Jurassic Park Ultimate Trilogy was released on DVD and Blu-ray on October 25, 2011, in North America. The first film was re-released in 3D on April 5, 2013.The fourth film, Jurassic World, was initially scheduled to be released in the summer of 2005, but was delayed numerous times and was ultimately released in June 2015. It became the first film to gross over $500 million worldwide in its opening weekend, and has grossed over $1.6 billion through the course of its theatrical run, making it the fifth highest-grossing film of all time. It was also the second highest-grossing film of 2015. When adjusted for monetary inflation, this film is the second highest grossing in the franchise after Jurassic Park. An animated film, Lego Jurassic World: The Indominus Escape, was released on October 18, 2016 with the home media release of Jurassic World, alongside a short film, Employee Safety Video. Another Lego short film, Lego Jurassic World: Rescue Blue, was also released in 2018.
A fifth film, Jurassic World: Fallen Kingdom, was released in June 2018. The film has grossed over $1.3 billion worldwide, making it the third Jurassic film to pass the billion dollar mark. It is the third highest-grossing film of 2018 and the 12th highest-grossing film of all time. A sixth film, tentatively titled Jurassic World 3, is scheduled to be released on June 11, 2021. As of 2000, the franchise had generated $5 billion in revenue, making it one of the highest-grossing media franchises of all time.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jurassic_Park</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0137523/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Fight Club</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>15 October 1999 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>David Fincher</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Fight Club is a 1999 film based on the 1996 novel by Chuck Palahniuk. It was directed by David Fincher and stars Brad Pitt, Edward Norton, and Helena Bonham Carter. Norton plays the unnamed narrator, who is discontent with his white-collar job. He forms a &quot;fight club&quot; with soap salesman Tyler Durden (Pitt), and becomes embroiled in a relationship with him and a destitute woman, Marla Singer (Bonham Carter).
Palahniuk's novel was optioned by 20th Century Fox producer Laura Ziskin, who hired Jim Uhls to write the film adaptation. Fincher was selected because of his enthusiasm for the story. He developed the script with Uhls and sought screenwriting advice from the cast and others in the film industry. He and the cast compared the film to Rebel Without a Cause (1955) and The Graduate (1967), with a theme of conflict between Generation X and the value system of advertising. Fincher used the homoerotic overtones of Palahniuk's novel to make audiences uncomfortable and keep them from anticipating the twist ending.Studio executives did not like the film and restructured Fincher's marketing campaign to try to reduce anticipated losses. Fight Club failed to meet the studio's expectations at the box office and received polarized reviews, becoming one of the most controversial and talked-about films of the year. Critics praised the acting, directing, and themes, but debated the violence and moral ambiguity. Over time, however, critical and public reception towards the film has become largely positive, and the film found success with its DVD release, which established Fight Club as a cult film. It is now regarded by many as one of the greatest films of the 1990s and of all time.

</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fight_Club</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0080684/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Star Wars: Episode V</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>20 June 1980 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Irvin Kershner</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Star Wars: Episode IX is an upcoming American epic space opera film produced, co-written, and directed by J. J. Abrams. It is intended to be the third and final installment of the Star Wars sequel trilogy and the ninth installment of the main Star Wars film franchise, following The Force Awakens (2015) and The Last Jedi (2017). The film is produced by Lucasfilm and Bad Robot Productions and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
The film was announced after Disney's acquisition of Lucasfilm in October 2012, with Colin Trevorrow announced as the film's director in August 2015. In September 2017, Trevorrow left the project due to creative differences; he was replaced by Abrams, who previously directed The Force Awakens. Filming began in August 2018 at Pinewood Studios in London. Episode IX is set to be released on December 20, 2019 in the United States.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_Wars:_Episode_IX</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111161/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Shawshank Redemption</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>14 October 1994 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Frank Darabont</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Shawshank Redemption is a 1994 American drama film written and directed by Frank Darabont, based on the 1982 Stephen King novella Rita Hayworth and Shawshank Redemption. It tells the story of banker Andy Dufresne (Tim Robbins), who is sentenced to life in Shawshank State Penitentiary for the murder of his wife and her lover, despite his claims of innocence. Over the following two decades, he befriends a fellow prisoner, contraband smuggler Ellis &quot;Red&quot; Redding (Morgan Freeman), and becomes instrumental in a money laundering operation led by the prison warden Samuel Norton (Bob Gunton). William Sadler, Clancy Brown, Gil Bellows, and James Whitmore appear in supporting roles.
Darabont purchased the film rights to King's story in 1987, but development did not begin until five years later when he wrote the script over an eight-week period. Two weeks after submitting his script to the Castle Rock Entertainment film studio, Darabont secured a $25 million budget to produce The Shawshank Redemption, which started pre-production in January 1993. While the film is set in Maine, principal photography took place from June to August 1993 almost entirely in Mansfield, Ohio, with the Ohio State Reformatory serving as the eponymous penitentiary. The project attracted many stars of the time for the lead roles including Tom Hanks, Tom Cruise, and Kevin Costner. Thomas Newman provided the film's score.
While The Shawshank Redemption received positive reviews on its release, particularly for its story and the performances of Robbins and Freeman, it was a box office disappointment, earning only $16 million during its initial theatrical run. Many reasons were cited for its failure at the time, including competition from films such as Pulp Fiction and Forrest Gump, to the general unpopularity of prison films, lack of female characters, and even the title, which was considered to be confusing for audiences. Even so, it went on to receive multiple award nominations, including seven Academy Award nominations, and a theatrical re-release that, combined with international takings, increased the film's box office gross to $58.3 million.
Over 320,000 VHS copies were shipped throughout the United States, and based on its award nominations and word of mouth, it became one of the top rented films of 1995. The broadcast rights were acquired following the purchase of Castle Rock by the Turner Broadcasting System, and it was shown regularly on the TNT network starting in 1997, further increasing its popularity. It is now considered by many to be one of the greatest films of the 1990s. As of 2017, the film is still broadcast regularly, and is popular in several countries, with audience members and celebrities citing it as a source of inspiration, and naming the film as a favorite in various surveys. In 2015, the United States Library of Congress selected the film for preservation in the National Film Registry, finding it &quot;culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant&quot;.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Shawshank_Redemption</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071562/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Godfather: Part II</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>20 December 1974 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Francis Ford Coppola</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Godfather Part II is a 1974 American crime film produced and directed by Francis Ford Coppola from a screenplay co-written with Mario Puzo, starring Al Pacino and Robert De Niro. Partially based on Puzo's 1969 novel The Godfather, the film is both sequel and prequel to The Godfather, presenting parallel dramas: one picks up the 1958 story of Michael Corleone (Pacino), the new Don of the Corleone crime family, protecting the family business in the aftermath of an attempt on his life; the prequel covers the journey of his father, Vito Corleone (De Niro), from his Sicilian childhood to the founding of his family enterprise in New York City.
The Godfather Part II opened to mixed reviews from critics, many of whom praised its cinematography while finding its nonlinear narrative disorganized. It was nominated for eleven Academy Awards, and became the first sequel to win for Best Picture. Its six Oscar wins included Best Director for Coppola, Best Supporting Actor for De Niro and Best Adapted Screenplay for Coppola and Puzo. Pacino won the BAFTA Award for Best Actor and was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Actor.
Both The Godfather Part II and its predecessor remain highly influential films, especially in the gangster genre, and the former has been reevaluated. In 1997, the American Film Institute ranked it as the 32nd-greatest film in American film history and it retained this position 10 years later. Some have deemed it superior to the 1972 original. It was selected for preservation in the U.S. National Film Registry of the Library of Congress in 1993, being deemed &quot;culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant&quot;.The Godfather Part III, a further sequel, was released in 1990.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Godfather_Part_II</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0088763/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Back to the Future</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Comedy</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>3 July 1985 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Robert Zemeckis</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Back to the Future is a 1985 American science fiction film directed by Robert Zemeckis and written by Zemeckis and Bob Gale. It stars Michael J. Fox as teenager Marty McFly, who accidentally travels back in time to 1955, where he meets his future parents and becomes his mother's romantic interest. Christopher Lloyd portrays the eccentric scientist Dr. Emmett &quot;Doc&quot; Brown, inventor of the time-traveling DeLorean, who helps Marty repair history and return to 1985.
Zemeckis and Gale wrote the script after Gale wondered whether he would have befriended his father if they had attended school together. Film studios rejected it until the financial success of Zemeckis' Romancing the Stone. Zemeckis approached Steven Spielberg, who agreed to produce the project at Amblin Entertainment, with Universal Pictures as distributor. Fox was the first choice to play Marty, but he was busy filming his television series Family Ties, and Eric Stoltz was cast; after the filmmakers decided he was wrong for the role, a deal was struck to allow Fox to film Back to the Future without interrupting his television schedule.
Back to the Future was released on July 3, 1985 and it grossed over $381 million worldwide, becoming the highest-grossing film of 1985. It won the Hugo Award for Best Dramatic Presentation, the Saturn Award for Best Science Fiction Film, and the Academy Award for Best Sound Effects Editing. It received three Academy Award nominations, five BAFTA nominations, and four Golden Globe nominations, including Best Motion Picture (Musical or Comedy). In 2007, the Library of Congress selected it for preservation in the National Film Registry, and in June 2008 the American Film Institute's special AFI's 10 Top 10 designated it the 10th-best science fiction film. The film began a franchise including two sequels, Back to the Future Part II (1989) and Back to the Future Part III (1990), an animated series, theme park ride, and several video games.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Back_to_the_Future</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0468569/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Dark Knight</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>18 July 2008 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Christopher Nolan</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Dark Knight Rises is a 2012 American-British superhero film directed by Christopher Nolan, who co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Jonathan Nolan, and the story with David S. Goyer. Featuring the DC Comics character Batman, the film is the final installment in Nolan's The Dark Knight Trilogy, and the sequel to The Dark Knight (2008). Christian Bale reprises the lead role of Bruce Wayne/Batman, with a returning cast of allies: Michael Caine as Alfred Pennyworth, Gary Oldman as James Gordon, and Morgan Freeman as Lucius Fox. The film introduces Selina Kyle (Anne Hathaway) and Bane (Tom Hardy). Eight years after the events of The Dark Knight, merciless revolutionary Bane forces an older Bruce Wayne to resume his role as Batman and save Gotham City from nuclear destruction.
Christopher Nolan was hesitant about returning to the series for a second time, but agreed after developing a story with his brother and Goyer that he felt would conclude the series on a satisfactory note. Nolan drew inspiration from Bane's comic book debut in the 1993 &quot;Knightfall&quot; storyline, the 1986 series The Dark Knight Returns, and the 1999 storyline &quot;No Man's Land&quot;. Filming took place from May to November 2011 in locations including Jodhpur, London, Nottingham, Glasgow, Los Angeles, New York City, Newark, and Pittsburgh. Nolan used IMAX 70 mm film cameras for much of the filming, including the first six minutes of the film, to optimize the quality of the picture. A vehicle variation of the Batplane and Batcopter termed the &quot;Bat&quot;, an underground prison set, and a new Batcave set were created specifically for the film. As with The Dark Knight, viral marketing campaigns began early during production. When filming concluded, Warner Bros. refocused its campaign: developing promotional websites, releasing the first six minutes of the film, screening theatrical trailers, and sending out information regarding the film's plot.
The Dark Knight Rises premiered in New York City on July 16, 2012. The film was released in the United States and the United Kingdom on July 20, 2012. It received positive reviews from critics, many of whom praised the action sequences, cast, musical score and the manner in which it concludes the trilogy, and named it one of the best films of 2012. Like its predecessor, the film grossed over $1 billion worldwide at the box office, making it the second film in the Batman film series to earn $1 billion. In addition to being Nolan's highest-grossing film, it is the 24th highest-grossing film of all time (7th at the time of release), the third highest-grossing film of 2012, and the eighth highest-grossing superhero film.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Dark_Knight_Rises</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1375666/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Inception</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>16 July 2010 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Christopher Nolan</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Inception is a 2010 science fiction action film written, co-produced, and directed by Christopher Nolan, and co-produced by Emma Thomas. The film stars Leonardo DiCaprio as a professional thief who steals information by infiltrating the subconscious, and is offered a chance to have his criminal history erased as payment for the implantation of another person's idea into a target's subconscious. The ensemble cast additionally includes Ken Watanabe, Joseph Gordon-Levitt, Marion Cotillard, Ellen Page, Tom Hardy, Dileep Rao, Cillian Murphy, Tom Berenger, and Michael Caine.
After the 2002 completion of Insomnia, Nolan presented to Warner Bros. a written 80-page treatment about a horror film envisioning &quot;dream stealers&quot; based on lucid dreaming. Deciding he needed more experience before tackling a production of this magnitude and complexity, Nolan retired the project and instead worked on 2005's Batman Begins, 2006's The Prestige, and The Dark Knight in 2008. The treatment was revised over 6 months and was purchased by Warner in February 2009. Inception was filmed in six countries, beginning in Tokyo on June 19 and ending in Canada on November 22. Its official budget was $160 million, split between Warner Bros and Legendary. Nolan's reputation and success with The Dark Knight helped secure the film's $100 million in advertising expenditure.
Inception's première was held in London on July 8, 2010; it was released in both conventional and IMAX theaters beginning on July 16, 2010. Inception grossed over $828 million worldwide, becoming the fourth highest-grossing film of 2010. The home video market also had strong results, with $68 million in DVD and Blu-ray sales. Inception opened to acclaim from critics, who praised its screenplay, visual effects, score, and ensemble cast. It won four Academy Awards for Best Cinematography, Best Sound Editing, Best Sound Mixing, and Best Visual Effects, and was nominated for four more: Best Picture, Best Original Screenplay, Best Art Direction, and Best Original Score.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inception</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0099685/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Goodfellas</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>21 September 1990 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Martin Scorsese</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Goodfellas (stylized GoodFellas) is a 1990 American crime film directed by Martin Scorsese. It is an adaptation of the 1985 non-fiction book Wiseguy by Nicholas Pileggi, who co-wrote the screenplay with Scorsese. The film narrates the rise and fall of mob associate Henry Hill and his friends and family from 1955 to 1980.
Scorsese initially titled the film Wise Guy and postponed making it; later, he and Pileggi changed the title to Goodfellas. To prepare for their roles in the film, Robert De Niro, Joe Pesci, and Ray Liotta often spoke with Pileggi, who shared research material left over from writing the book. According to Pesci, improvisation and ad-libbing came out of rehearsals wherein Scorsese gave the actors freedom to do whatever they wanted. The director made transcripts of these sessions, took the lines he liked best and put them into a revised script, which the cast worked from during principal photography.
Made on a budget of $25 million, Goodfellas grossed $46.8 million. It received positive reviews from critics and was nominated for six Academy Awards, including Best Picture and Best Director, with Pesci winning for Best Supporting Actor. The film won five awards from the British Academy of Film and Television Arts, including Best Film and Best Director. Additionally, Goodfellas was named the year's best film by various critics' groups.
Goodfellas has been called one of the greatest films in the crime genre. In 2000, it was deemed &quot;culturally, historically, and aesthetically significant&quot; and selected for preservation in the National Film Registry by the United States Library of Congress. Its content and style have been emulated in numerous other films and television shows.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goodfellas</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0133093/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Matrix</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>31 March 1999 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Lana Wachowski</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Matrix is a 1999 science fiction action film written and directed by The Wachowskis and starring Keanu Reeves, Laurence Fishburne, Carrie-Anne Moss, Hugo Weaving, and Joe Pantoliano. It depicts a dystopian future in which reality as perceived by most humans is actually a simulated reality called &quot;the Matrix&quot;, created by sentient machines to subdue the human population, while their bodies' heat and electrical activity are used as an energy source. Cybercriminal and computer programmer Neo learns this truth and is drawn into a rebellion against the machines, which involves other people who have been freed from the &quot;dream world&quot;.
The Matrix is known for popularizing a visual effect known as &quot;bullet time&quot;, in which the heightened perception of certain characters is represented by allowing the action within a shot to progress in slow-motion while the camera's viewpoint appears to move through the scene at normal speed. The film is an example of the cyberpunk subgenre. It contains numerous references to philosophical and religious ideas, and pays homage to texts such as Plato's Allegory of the Cave, Jean Baudrillard's Simulacra and Simulation and Lewis Carroll's Alice's Adventures in Wonderland. The Wachowskis' approach to action scenes drew upon their admiration for Japanese animation and martial arts films, and the film's use of fight choreographers and wire fu techniques from Hong Kong action cinema influenced subsequent Hollywood action film productions.
The Matrix was first released in the United States on March 31, 1999 and grossed over $460 million worldwide. It was well-received by critics and won four Academy Awards, as well as other accolades, including BAFTA Awards and Saturn Awards. Reviewers praised The Matrix for its innovative visual effects, cinematography and entertainment value. The film has since appeared in lists of the greatest science fiction films, and, in 2012, was added to the National Film Registry for preservation. The success of the film led to the release of two feature film sequels, both written and directed by the Wachowskis: The Matrix Reloaded and The Matrix Revolutions. The Matrix franchise was further expanded through the production of comic books, video games and animated short films, in which the Wachowskis were heavily involved, and even inspired books and theories on ideas in religion and philosophy.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Matrix</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0317248/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>City of God</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>13 February 2004 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Fernando Meirelles</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The City of God Against the Pagans (Latin: De civitate Dei contra paganos), often called The City of God, is a book of Christian philosophy written in Latin by Augustine of Hippo in the early 5th century AD. The book was in response to allegations that Christianity brought about the decline of Rome and is considered one of Augustine's most important works, standing alongside The Confessions, The Enchiridion, On Christian Doctrine, and On the Trinity. As a work of one of the most influential Church Fathers, The City of God is a cornerstone of Western thought, expounding on many profound questions of theology, such as the suffering of the righteous, the existence of evil, the conflict between free will and divine omniscience, and the doctrine of original sin.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_City_of_God</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120737/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>19 December 2001 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Peter Jackson</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring is a 2001 fantasy adventure film directed by Peter Jackson based on the first volume of J. R. R. Tolkien's The Lord of the Rings (1954–1955). It is the first instalment in The Lord of the Rings series, and was followed by The Two Towers (2002) and The Return of the King (2003), based on the second and third volumes of The Lord of the Rings.
Set in Middle-earth, the story tells of the Dark Lord Sauron (Sala Baker), who is seeking the One Ring. The Ring has found its way to the young hobbit Frodo Baggins (Elijah Wood). The fate of Middle-earth hangs in the balance as Frodo and eight companions who form the Fellowship of the Ring begin their journey to Mount Doom in the land of Mordor, the only place where the Ring can be destroyed.
Released on 10 December 2001, the film was highly acclaimed by critics and fans alike who considered it to be a landmark in film-making and an achievement in the fantasy film genre. It has continued to be featured on critic lists of the greatest fantasy films ever made, as of  2017.  The film earned over $871 million worldwide and became the second highest-grossing film of 2001 in the US and worldwide (behind Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone).
It was nominated for thirteen Oscars at the 74th Academy Awards ceremony, including Best Picture, Best Director, and Best Supporting Actor for McKellen, winning four for Best Cinematography, Best Makeup, Best Original Score, and Best Visual Effects. It also won four British Academy Film Awards, including Best Film and Best Director BAFTA awards. The Special Extended Edition was released to DVD on 12 November 2002 and to Blu-ray Disc on 28 June 2011. In 2007, The Fellowship of the Ring was voted No. 50 on the American Film Institute's list of 100 greatest American films. The AFI also voted it the second greatest fantasy film of all time during their 10 Top 10 special. The film ranks #24 on Empire's 2008 list of the 500 greatest movies of all time.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lord_of_the_Rings:_The_Fellowship_of_the_Ring</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0167261/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>18 December 2002 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Peter Jackson</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers is a 2002 fantasy adventure film directed by Peter Jackson and based on the second volume of J. R. R. Tolkien's novel The Lord of the Rings. It is the second instalment in The Lord of the Rings film series, preceded by The Fellowship of the Ring (2001) and concluding with The Return of the King (2003).
Continuing the plot of The Fellowship of the Ring, the film intercuts three storylines. Frodo and Sam continue their journey towards Mordor to destroy the One Ring, meeting and joined by Gollum, the ring's former owner. Aragorn, Legolas, and Gimli come to the war-torn nation of Rohan and are reunited with the resurrected Gandalf, before fighting at the Battle of Helm's Deep. Merry and Pippin escape capture, meet Treebeard the Ent, and help to plan an attack on Isengard.
Meeting high critical acclaim, the film was an enormous box-office success, earning over $926 million worldwide and is currently the 49th highest-grossing film of all time; and also the  highest-grossing film of 2002 (inflation-adjusted, it is the 62nd most successful film in North America). The film won numerous accolades and was nominated for six Academy Awards, including Best Picture, and won Best Visual Effects and Best Sound Editing.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lord_of_the_Rings:_The_Two_Towers</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0075314/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Taxi Driver</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>8 February 1976 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Martin Scorsese</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Taxi Driver is a 1976 American neo-noir psychological thriller film directed by Martin Scorsese, written by Paul Schrader, and starring Robert De Niro, Jodie Foster, Cybill Shepherd, Harvey Keitel, Peter Boyle, Albert Brooks and Leonard Harris. Set in a decaying New York City following the Vietnam War, the film tells the story of a lonely veteran (De Niro) working as a taxi driver, who descends into insanity as he plots to assassinate a presidential candidate (Harris) and then the pimp (Keitel) of an underage prostitute (Foster) whom he befriends.
Critically acclaimed upon release and nominated for four Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Taxi Driver won the Palme d'Or at the 1976 Cannes Film Festival. It is regularly cited by critics, film directors, and audiences alike as one of the greatest films of all time. In 2012, Sight &amp; Sound named it the 31st-best film ever in its decennial critics' poll, ranked with The Godfather Part II, and the fifth-greatest film of all time on its directors' poll. The film was considered &quot;culturally, historically or aesthetically&quot; significant by the US Library of Congress and was selected for preservation in the National Film Registry in 1994.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taxi_Driver</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0078748/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Alien</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Horror</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>22 June 1979 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Ridley Scott</value>
    </director>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0172495/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Gladiator</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>5 May 2000 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Ridley Scott</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>A gladiator (Latin: gladiator, &quot;swordsman&quot;, from gladius, &quot;sword&quot;) was an armed combatant who entertained audiences in the Roman Republic and Roman Empire in violent confrontations with other gladiators, wild animals, and condemned criminals. Some gladiators were volunteers who risked their lives and their legal and social standing by appearing in the arena. Most were despised as slaves, schooled under harsh conditions, socially marginalized, and segregated even in death.
Irrespective of their origin, gladiators offered spectators an example of Rome's martial ethics and, in fighting or dying well, they could inspire admiration and popular acclaim. They were celebrated in high and low art, and their value as entertainers was commemorated in precious and commonplace objects throughout the Roman world.
The origin of gladiatorial combat is open to debate. There is evidence of it in funeral rites during the Punic Wars of the 3rd century BC, and thereafter it rapidly became an essential feature of politics and social life in the Roman world. Its popularity led to its use in ever more lavish and costly games.
The gladiator games lasted for nearly a thousand years, reaching their peak between the 1st century BC and the 2nd century AD.  The games finally declined during the early 5th century after the adoption of Christianity as state church of the Roman Empire in 380, although beast hunts (venationes) continued into the 6th century.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gladiator</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0364569/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Oldboy</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Mystery</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>21 November 2003 (South Korea)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Chan-wook Park</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Oldboy is a 2013 American neo noir film, and a remake of Park Chan-wook's 2003 South Korean film of the same name. It was directed by Spike Lee and written by Mark Protosevich, the film stars Josh Brolin, Elizabeth Olsen and Sharlto Copley.
The film was released on November 27, 2013. It was the last film to be distributed by FilmDistrict, before Focus Features absorbed the company in October 2013. It received a mixed reception from both critics and audiences, with praise towards the acting and visual style, but criticism for the comparisons to the original and adding nothing new to the film. The film was a box office bomb, with one of the worst financial performances of Lee's directing career.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oldboy_(2013_film)</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0848228/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Avengers</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>4 May 2012 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Joss Whedon</value>
    </director>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1345836/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Dark Knight Rises</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>20 July 2012 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Christopher Nolan</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Dark Knight Rises is a 2012 American-British superhero film directed by Christopher Nolan, who co-wrote the screenplay with his brother Jonathan Nolan, and the story with David S. Goyer. Featuring the DC Comics character Batman, the film is the final installment in Nolan's The Dark Knight Trilogy, and the sequel to The Dark Knight (2008). Christian Bale reprises the lead role of Bruce Wayne/Batman, with a returning cast of allies: Michael Caine as Alfred Pennyworth, Gary Oldman as James Gordon, and Morgan Freeman as Lucius Fox. The film introduces Selina Kyle (Anne Hathaway) and Bane (Tom Hardy). Eight years after the events of The Dark Knight, merciless revolutionary Bane forces an older Bruce Wayne to resume his role as Batman and save Gotham City from nuclear destruction.
Christopher Nolan was hesitant about returning to the series for a second time, but agreed after developing a story with his brother and Goyer that he felt would conclude the series on a satisfactory note. Nolan drew inspiration from Bane's comic book debut in the 1993 &quot;Knightfall&quot; storyline, the 1986 series The Dark Knight Returns, and the 1999 storyline &quot;No Man's Land&quot;. Filming took place from May to November 2011 in locations including Jodhpur, London, Nottingham, Glasgow, Los Angeles, New York City, Newark, and Pittsburgh. Nolan used IMAX 70 mm film cameras for much of the filming, including the first six minutes of the film, to optimize the quality of the picture. A vehicle variation of the Batplane and Batcopter termed the &quot;Bat&quot;, an underground prison set, and a new Batcave set were created specifically for the film. As with The Dark Knight, viral marketing campaigns began early during production. When filming concluded, Warner Bros. refocused its campaign: developing promotional websites, releasing the first six minutes of the film, screening theatrical trailers, and sending out information regarding the film's plot.
The Dark Knight Rises premiered in New York City on July 16, 2012. The film was released in the United States and the United Kingdom on July 20, 2012. It received positive reviews from critics, many of whom praised the action sequences, cast, musical score and the manner in which it concludes the trilogy, and named it one of the best films of 2012. Like its predecessor, the film grossed over $1 billion worldwide at the box office, making it the second film in the Batman film series to earn $1 billion. In addition to being Nolan's highest-grossing film, it is the 24th highest-grossing film of all time (7th at the time of release), the third highest-grossing film of 2012, and the eighth highest-grossing superhero film.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Dark_Knight_Rises</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1853728/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Django Unchained</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Western</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>25 December 2012 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Quentin Tarantino</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Django Unchained is a 2012 American revisionist Western film written and directed by Quentin Tarantino, starring Jamie Foxx, Christoph Waltz, Leonardo DiCaprio, Kerry Washington, and Samuel L. Jackson, with Walton Goggins, Dennis Christopher, James Remar, and Don Johnson in supporting roles.  Set in the Old West and Antebellum South, it is a highly stylized tribute to Spaghetti Westerns, in particular the 1966 Italian film Django by Sergio Corbucci, whose star Franco Nero has a cameo appearance.
Development of Django Unchained began in 2007 when Tarantino was writing a book on Corbucci. By April 2011, Tarantino sent his final draft of the script to The Weinstein Company. Casting began in the summer of 2011, with Michael K. Williams and Will Smith being considered for the role of the title character before Foxx was cast. Principal photography took place from November 2011 to March 2012 in California, Wyoming and Louisiana.
Django Unchained premiered at the Ziegfeld Theatre in New York City on December 11, 2012, and was released on December 25, 2012, in the United States. The film was nominated for several film industry awards, including five Academy Awards. Waltz won several awards for his performance, among them Best Supporting Actor at the Golden Globes, BAFTAs, and Academy Awards. Tarantino won an Academy Award, a Golden Globe, and a BAFTA award for writing the film's original screenplay. The film grossed over $425 million worldwide in theaters against its $100 million budget, making it Tarantino's highest-grossing theatrical release.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Django_Unchained</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1136608/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Distrito 9</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>14 August 2009 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Neill Blomkamp</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>District 9 is a 2009 science fiction action film directed by Neill Blomkamp, written by Blomkamp and Terri Tatchell, and produced by Peter Jackson and Carolynne Cunningham. It is a co-production of New Zealand, the United States, and South Africa. The film stars Sharlto Copley, Jason Cope, and David James, and was adapted from Blomkamp's 2006 short film Alive in Joburg.
The film is partially presented in a found footage format by featuring fictional interviews, news footage, and video from surveillance cameras. The story, which explores themes of humanity, xenophobia, and social segregation, begins in an alternate 1982, when an alien ship appears over Johannesburg, South Africa. When a population of sick and malnourished insect-like aliens is found aboard the ship, the South African government confines them to an internment camp called District 9. Years later, during the government's relocation of the aliens to another camp, one of the confined aliens named Christopher Johnson tries to escape with his son and return home, crossing paths with a bureaucrat named Wikus van der Merwe. The title and premise of District 9 were inspired by events in District Six, Cape Town, during the apartheid era.
A viral marketing campaign for the film began in 2008 at San Diego Comic-Con, while the theatrical trailer debuted in July 2009. District 9 was released by TriStar Pictures on 14 August 2009, in North America and became a financial success, earning over $210 million at the box office. It also received acclaim from critics, who praised the film's direction, performances, themes, and story, and garnered numerous awards and nominations, including four Academy Award nominations for Best Picture, Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Visual Effects, and Best Film Editing.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/District_9</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114369/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Se7en</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Mystery</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>22 September 1995 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>David Fincher</value>
    </director>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0082971/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Raiders of the Lost Ark</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>12 June 1981 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Steven Spielberg</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Raiders of the Lost Ark is a 1981 American action adventure film directed by Steven Spielberg, written by Lawrence Kasdan from a story by George Lucas and Philip Kaufman. It was produced by Frank Marshall for Lucasfilm Ltd., with Lucas and Howard Kazanjian as executive producers.
The first installment in the Indiana Jones film franchise, it stars Harrison Ford as archaeologist Indiana Jones, who battles a group of Nazis searching for the Ark of the Covenant. It co-stars Karen Allen as Indiana's former lover, Marion Ravenwood; Paul Freeman as Indiana's rival, French archaeologist René Belloq; John Rhys-Davies as Indiana's sidekick, Sallah; Ronald Lacey as Gestapo agent Arnold Toht; and Denholm Elliott as Indiana's colleague, Marcus Brody.
The film originated from Lucas' desire to create a modern version of the serials of the 1930s and 1940s. Production was based at Elstree Studios, England, but filming also took place in La Rochelle, France, Tunisia, Hawaii, and California from June to September 1980.
Raiders of the Lost Ark became 1981's top-grossing film and remains one of the highest-grossing films. It was nominated for eight Academy Awards in 1982, including Best Picture, and won for Best Art Direction, Film Editing, Sound, and Visual Effects with a fifth Academy Award: a Special Achievement Award for Sound Effects Editing. It is often considered one of the greatest films ever made. In 1999, it was included in the U.S. Library of Congress' National Film Registry as &quot;culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant&quot;. The film began a franchise including several sequels, a television series, The Young Indiana Jones Chronicles (1992–1996), and numerous video games.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raiders_of_the_Lost_Ark</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0209144/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Memento</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Mystery</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>25 May 2001 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Christopher Nolan</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Memento is a 2000 American neo-noir psychological thriller film written and directed by Christopher Nolan, and produced by Suzanne and Jennifer Todd. The film's script was based on a pitch by Jonathan Nolan, who later wrote the story &quot;Memento Mori&quot; from the concept. It stars Guy Pearce, Carrie-Anne Moss, and Joe Pantoliano.
Pearce stars as a man who, as a result of a past trauma, has anterograde amnesia (the inability to form new memories) and has short-term memory loss approximately every five minutes. He is searching for the persons who attacked him and killed his wife, using an intricate system of Polaroid photographs and tattoos to track information he cannot remember. Memento is presented as two different sequences of scenes interspersed during the film: a series in black-and-white that is shown chronologically, and a series of color sequences shown in reverse order (simulating for the audience the mental state of the protagonist). The two sequences meet at the end of the film, producing one complete and cohesive narrative.Memento premiered on September 5, 2000, at the Venice International Film Festival and was released in European theaters starting in October. It became a blockbuster success, being acclaimed by critics who praised its nonlinear narrative structure and motifs of memory, perception, grief, and self-deception, and earning $39.7 million over a $9 million budget. It received numerous accolades, including Academy Award nominations for Best Original Screenplay and Best Film Editing. The film was subsequently ranked one of the best films of the 2000s by several critics and media outlets. Memento was considered &quot;culturally, historically or aesthetically&quot; significant by the US Library of Congress and was selected for preservation in the National Film Registry in 2017.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Memento_(film)</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0095327/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Grave of the Fireflies</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>War</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>24 November 1989 (Brazil)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Isao Takahata</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Grave of the Fireflies (火垂るの墓, Hotaru no Haka) is a 1988 Japanese animated war film based on the 1967 semi-autobiographical short story of the same name by Akiyuki Nosaka. It was written and directed by Isao Takahata, and animated by Studio Ghibli for the story's publisher Shinchosha Publishing (making it the only Studio Ghibli film under Tokuma Shoten ownership that had no involvement from them). The film stars Tsutomu Tatsumi, Ayano Shiraishi, Yoshiko Shinohara and Akemi Yamaguchi. Set in the city of Kobe, Japan, the film tells the story of two siblings, Seita and Setsuko, and their desperate struggle to survive during the final months of the Second World War.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grave_of_the_Fireflies</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0110413/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Léon: The Professional</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>18 November 1994 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Luc Besson</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Léon: The Professional (French: Léon), known as Leon in the UK (and originally titled The Professional in the US and Australia), is a 1994 English-language French thriller film written and directed by Luc Besson. It stars Jean Reno and Gary Oldman, and features the motion picture debut of Natalie Portman. In the film, Léon (Reno), a professional hitman, reluctantly takes in 12-year-old Mathilda (Portman), after her family is murdered by corrupt Drug Enforcement Administration agent Norman Stansfield (Oldman). Léon and Mathilda form an unusual relationship, as she becomes his protégée and learns the hitman's trade.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/L%C3%A9on:_The_Professional</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0910970/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>WALL·E</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Family</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>27 June 2008 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Andrew Stanton</value>
    </director>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0086250/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Scarface</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>9 December 1983 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Brian De Palma</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Scarface is a 1983 American crime film directed by Brian De Palma and written by Oliver Stone, a remake of the 1932 film of the same name. The film tells the story of Cuban refugee Tony Montana (Al Pacino) who arrives in 1980s Miami with nothing and rises to become a powerful drug kingpin. The cast also features Michelle Pfeiffer, Steven Bauer, Robert Loggia, F. Murray Abraham and Mary Elizabeth Mastrantonio.Scarface was released on December 9, 1983 and was a box office success, grossing $44 million. Initial critical reception was negative, with criticism over excessive violence and profanity and graphic drug usage. Some Cuban expatriates in Miami objected to the film's portrayal of Cubans as criminals and drug traffickers.
In the years that followed, the film has received reappraisal from critics, considered by some to be one of the best films in the crime genre. Screenwriters and directors such as Martin Scorsese have praised the film, which has been referenced extensively in pop culture, especially in rap and hip hop music as well as comic books, TV and video games. The film has long since become a cult classic.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scarface_(1983_film)</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0103064/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Terminator 2</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>3 July 1991 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>James Cameron</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Terminator 2: Judgment Day (often shortened to Terminator 2 or T2) is a 1991 American science-fiction action film co-written, produced, and directed by James Cameron. The film stars Arnold Schwarzenegger, Linda Hamilton, Robert Patrick, and Edward Furlong as its principal cast. It is the sequel to the 1984 film The Terminator, as well as the second installment in the Terminator franchise. Terminator 2 follows Sarah Connor (Hamilton) and her ten-year-old son John (Furlong) as they are pursued by a new, more advanced Terminator: the liquid metal, shapeshifting T-1000 (Patrick), sent back in time to kill John Connor and prevent him from becoming the leader of the human resistance. A second, less advanced Terminator (Schwarzenegger) is also sent back in time to protect John.
Terminator 2: Judgement Day was released in the United States on July 3, 1991. Its visual effects saw breakthroughs in computer-generated imagery, including the first use of natural human motion for a computer-generated character and the first partially computer-generated main character. It was a critical and commercial success and influenced popular culture, especially the use of visual effects in films. It received several accolades, including Academy Awards for Best Sound Editing, Best Sound Mixing, Best Makeup, and Best Visual Effects. The highest-grossing film of 1991 and of Schwarzenegger's career, Terminator 2 has since been named by several publications such as the American Film Institute as one of the greatest action films, science fiction films, and sequels of all time. The film was followed by another sequel in 2003 titled Terminator 3: Rise of the Machines, and the upcoming sixth film in the series will serve as an alternate sequel to the film and reboot the series from Rise of the Machines onwards, slated for a release in 2019. In 2017, Terminator 2 was re-released in 3D 4K resolution for AMC and Cineplex theaters, debuting at number one in the United Kingdom on its release weekend.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminator_2:_Judgment_Day</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0047478/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Seven Samurai</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>19 November 1956 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Akira Kurosawa</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Seven Samurai (七人の侍, Shichinin no Samurai) is a 1954 Japanese epic samurai drama film co-written, edited, and directed by Akira Kurosawa. The story takes place in 1586 during the Sengoku Period of Japanese history. It follows the story of a village of farmers that hire seven rōnin (masterless samurai) to combat bandits who will return after the harvest to steal their crops.
Since its release, Seven Samurai has consistently ranked highly in critics' lists of the greatest films, such as the BFI's Sight &amp; Sound and Rotten Tomatoes polls. It has remained highly influential, often seen as one of the most &quot;remade, reworked, referenced&quot; films in cinema.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seven_Samurai</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0245429/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Spirited Away</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Family</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>28 March 2003 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Hayao Miyazaki</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Spirited Away (Japanese: 千と千尋の神隠し, Hepburn: Sen to Chihiro no Kamikakushi, &quot;Sen and Chihiro's Spiriting Away&quot;) is a 2001 Japanese animated coming-of-age fantasy film written and directed by Hayao Miyazaki, animated by Studio Ghibli for Tokuma Shoten, Nippon Television Network, Dentsu, Buena Vista Home Entertainment, Tohokushinsha Film and Mitsubishi and distributed by Toho.  The film stars Rumi Hiiragi, Miyu Irino, Mari Natsuki, Takeshi Naito, Yasuko Sawaguchi, Tsunehiko Kamijō, Takehiko Ono, and Bunta Sugawara, and tells the story of Chihiro Ogino (Hiiragi), a sullen 10-year-old girl who, while moving to a new neighborhood, enters the spirit world. After her parents are transformed into pigs by the witch Yubaba (Natsuki), Chihiro takes a job working in Yubaba's bathhouse to find a way to free herself and her parents and return to the human world.
Miyazaki wrote the script after he decided the film would be based on the 10-year-old daughter of his friend, associate producer Seiji Okuda, who came to visit his house each summer. At the time, Miyazaki was developing two personal projects, but they were rejected. With a budget of US$19 million, production of Spirited Away began in 2000. Pixar director John Lasseter, a fan of Miyazaki, was approached by Walt Disney Pictures to supervise an English language translation for the film's North American release. Lasseter hired Kirk Wise as director and Donald W. Ernst as producer of the adaptation. Screenwriters Cindy Davis Hewitt and Donald H. Hewitt wrote the English language dialogue, which they wrote to match the characters' original Japanese language lip movements.The film was theatrically released in Japan on 20 July 2001 by distributor Toho, and became the most successful film in Japanese history, grossing over $289 million worldwide. The film overtook Titanic (at the time the top-grossing film worldwide) in the Japanese box office to become the highest-grossing film in Japanese history with a ¥30.4 billion total. Spirited Away received universal acclaim, and is frequently ranked among the greatest animated films of all time. It won the Academy Award for Best Animated Feature at the 75th Academy Awards, making it the first (and so far only) hand drawn and non-English language animated film to win such award; the Golden Bear at the 2002 Berlin International Film Festival, tied with Bloody Sunday; and is in the top 10 on the British Film Institute's list of &quot;Top 50 films for children up to the age of 14&quot;.In 2016, it was voted the fourth best film of the 21st century as picked by 177 film critics from around the world, making it the highest ranking animated film on the list. It was also named the second &quot;Best Film of the 21st Century So Far&quot; in 2017 by the New York Times.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spirited_Away</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0081505/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Shining</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Horror</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>13 June 1980 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Stanley Kubrick</value>
    </director>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0076759/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Star Wars: Episode IV</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>25 May 1977 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>George Lucas</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Star Wars (later retitled Star Wars: Episode IV – A New Hope) is a 1977 American epic space opera film written and directed by George Lucas. It is the first film in the original Star Wars trilogy and the beginning of the Star Wars franchise. Starring Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Peter Cushing, Alec Guinness, David Prowse, James Earl Jones, Anthony Daniels, Kenny Baker, and Peter Mayhew, the film focuses on the Rebel Alliance, led by Princess Leia (Fisher), and its attempt to destroy the Galactic Empire's space station, the Death Star.
Star Wars was released in theatres in the United States on May 25, 1977. It earned $461 million in the U.S. and $314 million overseas, totaling $775 million. It surpassed Jaws (1975) to become the highest-grossing film of all time until the release of E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial (1982). When adjusted for inflation, Star Wars is the second-highest-grossing film in North America, and the third-highest-grossing film in the world. It received ten Academy Award nominations (including Best Picture), winning seven. It was among the first films to be selected as part of the U.S. Library of Congress's National Film Registry as being &quot;culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant&quot;. At the time, it was the most recent film on the registry and the only one chosen from the 1970s. In 2005, the British Film Institute included it in their list of the 50 films you should see by the age of 14. Its soundtrack was added to the U.S. National Recording Registry in 2004. Today, it is regarded as one of the most important films in the history of motion pictures. It launched an industry of tie-in products, including spin-off TV series, novels, comic books, video games, amusement park attractions, and merchandise including toys, games, and clothing.
The film has been reissued multiple times at Lucas's behest, incorporating many changes including modified computer-generated effects, altered dialogue, re-edited shots, remixed soundtracks and added scenes. The film's success led to two critically and commercially successful sequels, The Empire Strikes Back in 1980 and Return of the Jedi in 1983, and later to a prequel trilogy, a sequel trilogy, and anthology films.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_Wars_(film)</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0266543/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Finding Nemo</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Comedy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>30 May 2003 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Andrew Stanton</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Finding Nemo is a 2003 American computer-animated adventure film produced by Pixar Animation Studios and released by Walt Disney Pictures. Written and directed by Andrew Stanton with co-direction by Lee Unkrich, the film stars the voices of Albert Brooks, Ellen DeGeneres, Alexander Gould, and Willem Dafoe. It tells the story of the overprotective ocellaris clownfish named Marlin who, along with a regal blue tang named Dory, searches for his abducted son Nemo all the way to Sydney Harbour. Along the way, Marlin learns to take risks and comes to terms with Nemo taking care of himself.
Finding Nemo was released on May 30, 2003; the film won the Academy Award for Best Animated Feature, and was nominated in three more categories, including Best Original Screenplay. Finding Nemo became the highest-grossing animated film at the time and was the second-highest-grossing film of 2003, earning a total of $871 million worldwide by the end of its initial theatrical run.The film is the best-selling DVD title of all time, with over 40 million copies sold as of  2006, and was the highest-grossing G-rated film of all time before Pixar's own Toy Story 3 overtook it. The film was re-released in 3D in 2012. In 2008, the American Film Institute named it the 10th greatest animated film ever made as part of their 10 Top 10 lists. In a 2016 poll of international critics conducted by BBC, Finding Nemo was voted one of the 100 greatest motion pictures since 2000. A sequel, Finding Dory, was released on June 17, 2016 in the United States.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finding_Nemo</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120586/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>American History X</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>20 November 1998 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Tony Kaye</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>American History X is a 1998 American crime drama film directed by Tony Kaye and written by David McKenna. It stars Edward Norton and Edward Furlong, and features Fairuza Balk, Stacy Keach, Elliott Gould, Avery Brooks, Ethan Suplee, and Beverly D'Angelo. The film was released in the United States on October 30, 1998, and was distributed by New Line Cinema.
The film tells the story of two brothers from Venice, Los Angeles who become involved in the neo-Nazi movement. The older brother serves three years in prison for voluntary manslaughter, changes his beliefs and tries to prevent his brother from going down the same path. The film is told in the style of nonlinear narrative. Made on a budget of $20 million, the film grossed $24 million at the worldwide box office.
Critics mostly praised the film and Norton's performance, which earned him an Academy Award nomination for Best Actor. In September 2008, Empire magazine named it the 311th Greatest Movie of All Time.

</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_History_X</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0169547/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>American Beauty</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>1 October 1999 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Sam Mendes</value>
    </director>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0105236/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Reservoir Dogs</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>4 June 1993 (Brazil)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Quentin Tarantino</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Reservoir Dogs is a 1992 American heist film written and directed by Quentin Tarantino in his feature-length debut. It stars Harvey Keitel, Tim Roth, Chris Penn, Steve Buscemi, Lawrence Tierney, Michael Madsen,  Tarantino, and criminal-turned-author Edward Bunker, as diamond thieves whose planned heist of a jewelry store goes terribly wrong. The film depicts the events before and after the heist. Kirk Baltz, Randy Brooks and Steven Wright also play supporting roles. It incorporates many motifs that have become Tarantino's hallmarks: violent crime, pop culture references, profanity, and nonlinear storytelling.
The film is regarded as a classic of independent film and a cult film, and was named &quot;Greatest Independent Film of all Time&quot; by Empire. Although controversial for its depictions of violence and use of profanity, Reservoir Dogs was generally well received, with the cast being praised by many critics. Despite not being heavily promoted during its theatrical run, the film became a modest success in the United States after grossing $2.8 million against its $1.2 million budget, and was more successful in the United Kingdom, grossing nearly £6.5 million. It achieved higher popularity after the success of Tarantino's next film, Pulp Fiction (1994). A soundtrack was released featuring songs used in the film, which are mostly from the 1970s.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reservoir_Dogs</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0361748/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Inglourious Basterds</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>War</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>21 August 2009 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Quentin Tarantino</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Inglourious Basterds is a 2009 war film written and directed by Quentin Tarantino and starring Brad Pitt, Christoph Waltz, Michael Fassbender, Eli Roth, Diane Kruger, Til Schweiger, and Mélanie Laurent. The film tells the alternate history story of two plots to assassinate Nazi Germany's leadership, one planned by Shosanna Dreyfus (Laurent), a young French Jewish cinema proprietor, and the other by a team of Jewish American soldiers led by First Lieutenant Aldo Raine (Pitt). Christoph Waltz co-stars as Hans Landa, an SS colonel tracking down Raine's group who is connected to Shosanna's past. The film's title was inspired by Italian director Enzo G. Castellari's macaroni combat film The Inglorious Bastards (1978).
Tarantino wrote the script in 1998, but struggled with the ending, and chose instead to direct the two-part film Kill Bill. After directing Death Proof in 2007, Tarantino returned to work on Inglourious Basterds. A co-production of the United States and Germany, the film began principal photography in October 2008 and was filmed in Germany and France with a $70 million production budget. It premiered on May 20, 2009, at the 62nd Cannes Film Festival, and received a wide release in theaters in the United States and Europe in August 2009 by The Weinstein Company and Universal Pictures.
Inglourious Basterds grossed over $321 million in theaters worldwide, making it Tarantino's highest-grossing film until the release of Django Unchained (2012); it remains his second-highest-grossing film. It received multiple awards and nominations, among them eight Academy Award nominations, including Best Picture, Best Director and Best Original Screenplay. For his role as Landa, Waltz won the Cannes Film Festival's Best Actor Award, as well as the BAFTA, Screen Actors Guild, Golden Globe, and Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inglourious_Basterds</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0401792/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Sin City</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>1 April 2005 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Frank Miller</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Sin City is a series of neo-noir comics by American comic book writer Frank Miller. The first story originally appeared in Dark Horse Presents Fifth Anniversary Special (April 1991), and continued in Dark Horse Presents #51–62 from May 1991 to June 1992, under the title of Sin City, serialized in thirteen parts. Several other stories of variable lengths have followed. The intertwining stories, with frequently recurring characters, take place in Basin City.
A film adaptation of Sin City, co-directed by Robert Rodriguez and Frank Miller, was released on April 1, 2005. A sequel, Sin City: A Dame To Kill For, was released on August 22, 2014. Dimension Films is developing a soft reboot of the series for television, Stephen L’Heureux who produced the second film will oversee the series with Sin City creator Frank Miller. This will be with new characters and timelines and be more like the comics rather than the films.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sin_City</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0796366/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Star Trek</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>8 May 2009 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>J.J. Abrams</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Star Trek is an American space opera media franchise based on the science fiction television series created by Gene Roddenberry. The first television series, simply called Star Trek and now referred to as &quot;The Original Series&quot;, debuted in 1966 and aired for three seasons on the television network NBC. It followed the interstellar adventures of Captain James T. Kirk (William Shatner) and his crew aboard the starship USS Enterprise, a space exploration vessel, built by the United Federation of Planets in the twenty-third century. The Star Trek canon of the franchise includes The Original Series, an animated series, five spin-off television series, the film franchise, and further adaptations in several media.
In creating Star Trek, Roddenberry was inspired by the Horatio Hornblower novels, the satirical book Gulliver's Travels, and by works of western genre such as the television series Wagon Train. These adventures continued in the 22-episode Star Trek: The Animated Series and six feature films. Four spin-off television series were eventually produced: Star Trek: The Next Generation followed the crew of a new starship Enterprise set a century after the original series; Star Trek: Deep Space Nine and Star Trek: Voyager set contemporaneously with The Next Generation; and Star Trek: Enterprise set before the original series in the early days of human interstellar travel. The most recent Star Trek TV series, entitled Star Trek: Discovery, premiered on CBS and was later made available exclusively on the digital platform CBS All Access.  The adventures of The Next Generation crew continued in four additional feature films. In 2009, the film franchise underwent a &quot;reboot&quot; set in an alternate timeline, or &quot;Kelvin Timeline,&quot; entitled simply Star Trek. This film featured a new cast portraying younger versions of the crew from the original show; their adventures were continued in the sequel film, Star Trek Into Darkness (2013). The thirteenth film feature and sequel, Star Trek Beyond (2016), was released to coincide with the franchise's 50th anniversary.
Star Trek has been a cult phenomenon for decades. Fans of the franchise are called Trekkies or Trekkers. The franchise spans a wide range of spin-offs including games, figurines, novels, toys, and comics. Star Trek had a themed attraction in Las Vegas that opened in 1998 and closed in September 2008. At least two museum exhibits of props travel the world. The series has its own full-fledged constructed language, Klingon. Several parodies have been made of Star Trek. In addition, viewers have produced several fan productions. As of July 2016, the franchise had generated $10 billion in revenue, making Star Trek one of the highest-grossing media franchises of all time.
Star Trek is noted for its cultural influence beyond works of science fiction. The franchise is also noted for its progressive civil rights stances. The Original Series included one of television's first multiracial casts. Star Trek references may be found throughout popular culture from movies such as the submarine thriller Crimson Tide to the animated series South Park.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_Trek</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109830/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Forrest Gump</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Romance</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>6 July 1994 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Robert Zemeckis</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Forrest Gump is a 1994 American romantic comedy-drama film based on the 1986 novel of the same name by Winston Groom. It was directed by Robert Zemeckis and written by Eric Roth, and stars Tom Hanks, Robin Wright, Gary Sinise, Mykelti Williamson, and Sally Field. The story depicts several decades in the life of Forrest Gump (Hanks), a slow-witted but kind-hearted man from Alabama who witnesses several defining historical events in the 20th century in the United States.
The film differs substantially from the novel. Principal photography took place in late 1993, mainly in Georgia, North Carolina, and South Carolina. Extensive visual effects were used to incorporate Hanks into archived footage and develop other scenes. The soundtrack features songs reflecting the different periods seen in the film.
Released in the United States on July 6, 1994, Forrest Gump received favorable reviews for Zemeckis' directing, Hanks' performance, visual effects, and script. The film was a massive success at the box office; it became the top-grossing film in North America released that year and earned over US$677 million worldwide during its theatrical run, making it the second highest-grossing film of 1994. The soundtrack sold over 12 million copies. Forrest Gump won the Academy Awards for Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor for Hanks, Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Visual Effects, and Best Film Editing. It won many other awards and nominations, including Golden Globes, People's Choice Awards, and Young Artist Awards.
Varying interpretations have been made of the protagonist and the film's political symbolism. In 1996, a restaurant based on the film, Bubba Gump Shrimp Company, opened, and has since expanded to locations worldwide. In 2011, the Library of Congress selected the film for preservation in the United States National Film Registry as being &quot;culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant&quot;.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Forrest_Gump</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0102926/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Silence of the Lambs</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>14 February 1991 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Jonathan Demme</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Silence of the Lambs is a 1991 American horror-thriller film directed by Jonathan Demme from a screenplay written by Ted Tally, adapted from Thomas Harris's 1988 novel of the same name. The film stars Jodie Foster, Anthony Hopkins, Scott Glenn, Ted Levine, and Anthony Heald. In the film, Clarice Starling, a young FBI trainee, seeks the advice of the imprisoned Dr. Hannibal Lecter, a brilliant psychiatrist and cannibalistic serial killer to apprehend another serial killer, known only as &quot;Buffalo Bill&quot;, who skins his female victims' corpses. The novel was Harris's first and second respectively to feature the characters of Starling and Lecter, and was the second adaptation of a Harris novel to feature Lecter, preceded by the Michael Mann-directed Manhunter (1986).
The Silence of the Lambs was released on February 14, 1991, and grossed $272.7 million worldwide against its $19 million budget, becoming the fifth-highest grossing film of 1991 worldwide. The film premiered at the 41st Berlin International Film Festival, where it competed for the Golden Bear, while Demme received the Silver Bear for Best Director.
Critically acclaimed upon release, it became only the third film, (the other two being It Happened One Night and One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest), to win Academy Awards in all the top five categories: Best Picture, Best Director, Best Actor, Best Actress, and Best Adapted Screenplay. It is also the first (and so far only) Best Picture winner widely considered to be a horror film, and only the third such film to be nominated in the category, after The Exorcist (1973) and Jaws (1975).It is regularly cited by critics, film directors, and audiences alike as one of the greatest and most influential films of all time. In 2018, Empire ranked it 48th, on their list of 500 greatest movies of all time.  The American Film Institute, ranked it as the 5th greatest and most influential thriller film of all time. The film is considered &quot;culturally, historically or aesthetically&quot; significant by the U.S. Library of Congress and was selected to be preserved in the National Film Registry in 2011. A sequel titled Hannibal was released in 2001, in which Hopkins reprised his role. It was followed by two prequels: Red Dragon (2002) and Hannibal Rising (2007).</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Silence_of_the_Lambs_(film)</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0325980/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>9 July 2003 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Gore Verbinski</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl is a 2003 American fantasy swashbuckler film directed by Gore Verbinski and the first film in the Pirates of the Caribbean film series. Produced by Walt Disney Pictures and Jerry Bruckheimer, the film is based on Walt Disney's Pirates of the Caribbean attraction at Disney theme parks. The story follows pirate Jack Sparrow (Johnny Depp) and blacksmith Will Turner (Orlando Bloom) as they rescue the kidnapped Elizabeth Swann (Keira Knightley) from the cursed crew of the Black Pearl, captained by Hector Barbossa (Geoffrey Rush), who become undead skeletons at night.
Jay Wolpert developed a script  in 2001, and Stuart Beattie rewrote it in early 2002. Around that time, producer Jerry Bruckheimer became involved in the project; he had Ted Elliott and Terry Rossio work on the script, adding the plot device of a supernatural curse to the story to bring it in line with the original theme park ride. Filming took place from October 2002 to March 2003 in Saint Vincent and the Grenadines and on sets constructed around Los Angeles, California. It was also significant in being the first film released under the Walt Disney Pictures banner to be rated PG-13 by the MPAA.
The film's world premiere was held at Disneyland Park in Anaheim, California on June 28, 2003. Despite low expectations, the film was huge box office success, grossing over $654 million worldwide; making it the fourth highest-grossing film of 2003. It received generally positive reviews from critics, with many considering it to be the best entry in the series; the film was praised for the performances (particularly from Depp), action sequences, score, and visuals, but was criticized for its writing and length. The film has been widely seen as the film launched Depp as a box office leading man after many years as a cult movie star. Depp won the Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Male Actor in a Leading Role and earned him nominations for the Academy Award for Best Actor, BAFTA Award for Best Actor in a Leading Role, and Golden Globe Award for Best Actor – Motion Picture Musical or Comedy. The Curse of the Black Pearl was also nominated for four other Academy Awards and BAFTAs. The film became the first in a franchise, with two back-to-back sequels, Dead Man's Chest and At World's End, released in 2006 and 2007. Two more sequels, On Stranger Tides and Dead Men Tell No Tales, were released in 2011 and 2017 respectively.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pirates_of_the_Caribbean:_The_Curse_of_the_Black_Pearl</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0903624/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Family</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>14 December 2012 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Peter Jackson</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey is a 2012 epic high fantasy adventure film directed by Peter Jackson. It is the first installment in a three-part film adaptation based on J. R. R. Tolkien’s 1937 novel The Hobbit. It is followed by The Desolation of Smaug (2013) and The Battle of the Five Armies (2014), and together they act as a prequel to Jackson's The Lord of the Rings film trilogy. The film's screenplay was written by Jackson, his longtime collaborators Fran Walsh and Philippa Boyens, and Guillermo del Toro, who was originally chosen to direct the film before leaving the project in 2010.
The story is set in Middle-earth seventy-seven years before the main events of The Lord of the Rings, and portions of the film are adapted from the appendices to Tolkien's The Return of the King. An Unexpected Journey tells the tale of Bilbo Baggins (Martin Freeman), who is convinced by the wizard Gandalf (Ian McKellen) to accompany thirteen Dwarves, led by Thorin Oakenshield (Richard Armitage), on a quest to reclaim the Lonely Mountain from the dragon Smaug. The ensemble cast also includes James Nesbitt, Ken Stott, Cate Blanchett, Ian Holm, Christopher Lee, Hugo Weaving, Elijah Wood and Andy Serkis, and features Sylvester McCoy, Barry Humphries and Manu Bennett.
An Unexpected Journey premiered on 28 November 2012 in New Zealand and was released internationally on 12 December 2012. The film grossed over $1.021 billion at the box office, surpassing both The Fellowship of the Ring and The Two Towers nominally, becoming the fourth highest-grossing film of 2012 and the 35th highest-grossing film of all time. Receiving mixed reviews from critics, the film was nominated for three Academy Awards for Best Visual Effects, Best Production Design, and Best Makeup and Hairstyling. It was also nominated for three British Academy Film Awards.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hobbit:_An_Unexpected_Journey</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1201607/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows: Part 2</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>15 July 2011 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>David Yates</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows – Part 2 is a 2011 fantasy film directed by David Yates and distributed by Warner Bros. Pictures. It is the second of two cinematic parts based on J. K. Rowling’s 2007 novel of the same name. The film, which is the eighth and final instalment in the Harry Potter film series, was written by Steve Kloves and produced by David Heyman, David Barron, and Rowling. The story continues to follow Harry Potter's quest to find and destroy Lord Voldemort's Horcruxes in order to stop him once and for all.
The film stars Daniel Radcliffe as Harry Potter, alongside Rupert Grint and Emma Watson as Harry's best friends, Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger. Principal photography began on 19 February 2009, and was completed on 12 June 2010, with reshoots taking place in December 2010, more than ten years after filming started on the first instalment of the series. Part 2 was released in 2D, 3-D and IMAX cinemas worldwide from 13–15 July 2011, and is the only Harry Potter film to be released in 3-D.The film became a commercial success and was critically acclaimed, and one of the best reviewed films of 2011, with the acting, Yates's direction, musical score, visual effects, cinematography, action sequences, and satisfying conclusion of the saga earning notable praise. At the box office, Part 2 claimed the worldwide opening weekend record, earning $483.2 million, as well as setting opening day and opening weekend records in various countries. As of  2018, the film is the tenth-highest-grossing film of all time. It became the highest-grossing film of 2011, the highest-grossing film in the Harry Potter series, and the ninth film to gross over $1 billion.The Blu-ray and DVD sets were released on 11 November 2011 in the United States and on 2 December 2011 in the United Kingdom. The film was also released in the Harry Potter: Complete 8-Film Collection box set on DVD and Blu-ray, which included all eight films and new special features. Part 1 and Part 2 were released as a combo pack on DVD and Blu-ray on 11 November 2011 in Canada.
The film won several awards and was nominated for many more, including three nominations at the Academy Awards for Best Art Direction, Best Makeup and Best Visual Effects.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Potter_and_the_Deathly_Hallows_%E2%80%93_Part_2</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0086190/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Star Wars: Episode VI</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>25 May 1983 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Richard Marquand</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Return of the Jedi (also known as Star Wars: Episode VI – Return of the Jedi)  is a 1983 American epic space opera film directed by Richard Marquand. The screenplay by Lawrence Kasdan and George Lucas was from a story by Lucas, who was also the executive producer. It is the third and final installment in the original Star Wars trilogy and the first film to use THX technology. The film is set one year after The Empire Strikes Back and was produced by Howard Kazanjian for Lucasfilm Ltd. The film stars Mark Hamill, Harrison Ford, Carrie Fisher, Billy Dee Williams, Anthony Daniels, David Prowse, Kenny Baker, Peter Mayhew and Frank Oz.
The Galactic Empire, under the direction of the ruthless Emperor, is constructing a second Death Star in order to crush the Rebel Alliance once and for all. Since the Emperor plans to personally oversee the final stages of its construction, the Rebel Fleet launches a full-scale attack on the Death Star in order to prevent its completion and kill the Emperor, effectively bringing an end to the Empire's hold over the galaxy. Meanwhile, Luke Skywalker, a Jedi Knight, struggles to bring his father Darth Vader back to the light side of the Force.
David Lynch and David Cronenberg were considered to direct the project before Marquand signed on as director. The production team relied on Lucas' storyboards during pre-production. While writing the shooting script, Lucas, Kasdan, Marquand, and producer Howard Kazanjian spent two weeks in conference discussing ideas to construct it. Kazanjian's schedule pushed shooting to begin a few weeks early to allow Industrial Light &amp; Magic more time to work on the film's effects in post-production. Filming took place in England, California, and Arizona from January to May 1982 (1982-05). Strict secrecy surrounded the production and the film used the working title Blue Harvest to prevent price gouging.
The film was released in theaters on May 25, 1983, six years to the day after the release of the first film, receiving mostly positive reviews. The film grossed between $475 million and $572 million worldwide.  Several home video and theatrical releases and revisions to the film followed over the next 20 years. 32 years after the film's original release, it was followed by a sequel trilogy, beginning in 2015 with The Force Awakens.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Return_of_the_Jedi</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0266697/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Kill Bill: Vol. 1</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Crime</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>10 October 2003 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Quentin Tarantino</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Kill Bill: Volume 1 is a 2003 American martial arts film written and directed by Quentin Tarantino. It stars Uma Thurman as the Bride, who swears revenge on a team of assassins (Lucy Liu, Michael Madsen, Daryl Hannah, and Vivica A. Fox) and their leader Bill (David Carradine) after they try to kill her and her unborn child. Her journey takes her to Japan, where she battles the Tokyo yakuza.
Tarantino conceived Kill Bill as an homage to grindhouse cinema including martial arts films, samurai cinema, blaxploitation films, and spaghetti westerns. It features an anime sequence animated by Production I.G. It is the first of two Kill Bill films made in a single production; the films were originally set for a single release, but the film, with a runtime of over four hours, was divided in two. Volume 1 became Tarantino's highest-grossing film up to that point, earning over $180 million at the box office. Kill Bill: Volume 2 was released on April 16, 2004.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kill_Bill:_Volume_1</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0096283/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>My Neighbor Totoro</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Family</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>8 March 1995 (Brazil)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Hayao Miyazaki</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>My Neighbor Totoro (Japanese: となりのトトロ, Hepburn: Tonari no Totoro) is a 1988 Japanese animated fantasy film written and directed by Hayao Miyazaki and animated by Studio Ghibli for Tokuma Shoten. The film—which stars the voice actors Noriko Hidaka, Chika Sakamoto, and Hitoshi Takagi—tells the story of the two young daughters (Satsuki and Mei) of a professor and their interactions with friendly wood spirits in postwar rural Japan. The film won the Animage Anime Grand Prix prize and the Mainichi Film Award and Kinema Junpo Award for Best Film in 1988. It also received the Special Award at the Blue Ribbon Awards in the same year.
In 1989, Streamline Pictures produced an exclusive dub for use on transpacific flights by Japan Airlines. Troma Films, under their 50th St. Films banner, distributed the dub of the film co-produced by Jerry Beck. This dub was released to United States theaters in 1993, on VHS and laserdisc in the United States by Fox Video in 1994, and on DVD in 2002. The rights to this dub expired in 2004, so it was re-released by Walt Disney Home Entertainment on 7 March 2006 with a new dub cast. This version was also released in Australia by Madman on 15 March 2006 and in the UK by Optimum Releasing on 27 March 2006. This DVD release is the first version of the film in the United States to include both Japanese and English language tracks, as Fox did not have the rights to the Japanese audio track for their version.
My Neighbor Totoro was critically acclaimed and has amassed a worldwide cult following in the years after its release. The film and its titular character, Totoro, have become cultural icons. My Neighbor Totoro ranked 41st in Empire magazine's &quot;The 100 Best Films Of World Cinema&quot; in 2010, and Totoro was ranked 18th on Empire's 50 Best Animated Film Characters list. A list of the greatest animated films compiled by Terry Gilliam in Time Out ranked the film number 1. A similar list compiled by the editors of Time Out ranked the film number 3. The character made multiple cameo appearances in a number of Studio Ghibli films and video games and also serves as the mascot for the studio and is recognized as one of the most popular characters in Japanese animation. Totoro was ranked 24th on IGN's top 25 anime characters.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/My_Neighbor_Totoro</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0454876/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Life of Pi</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>21 November 2012 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Ang Lee</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Life of Pi is a Canadian fantasy adventure novel by Yann Martel published in 2001. The protagonist is Piscine Molitor &quot;Pi&quot; Patel, an Indian boy from Pondicherry who explores issues of spirituality and practicality from an early age. He survives 227 days after a shipwreck while stranded on a lifeboat in the Pacific Ocean with a Bengal tiger named Richard Parker.
The novel has sold more than ten million copies worldwide. It was rejected by at least five London publishing houses before being accepted by Knopf Canada, which published it in September 2001. The UK edition won the Man Booker Prize for Fiction the following year. It was also chosen for CBC Radio's Canada Reads 2003, where it was championed by author Nancy Lee.The French translation L'Histoire de Pi was chosen in the French CBC version of the contest Le combat des livres, where it was championed by Louise Forestier. The novel won the 2003 Boeke Prize, a South African novel award. In 2004, it won the Asian/Pacific American Award for Literature in Best Adult Fiction for years 2001–2003. In 2012 it was adapted into a feature film directed by Ang Lee with a screenplay by David Magee.

</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Life_of_Pi</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0108052/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Schindler's List</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Biography</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>History</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>4 February 1994 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Steven Spielberg</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Schindler's List is a 1993 American epic historical period drama film directed and co-produced by Steven Spielberg and written by Steven Zaillian. It is based on the novel Schindler's Ark by Australian novelist Thomas Keneally. The film follows Oskar Schindler, a Sudeten German businessman, who saved the lives of more than a thousand mostly Polish-Jewish refugees from the Holocaust by employing them in his factories during World War II. It stars Liam Neeson as Schindler, Ralph Fiennes as SS officer Amon Göth, and Ben Kingsley as Schindler's Jewish accountant Itzhak Stern.
Ideas for a film about the Schindlerjuden (Schindler Jews) were proposed as early as 1963. Poldek Pfefferberg, one of the Schindlerjuden, made it his life's mission to tell the story of Schindler. Spielberg became interested in the story when executive Sidney Sheinberg sent him a book review of Schindler's Ark. Universal Pictures bought the rights to the novel, but Spielberg, unsure if he was ready to make a film about the Holocaust, tried to pass the project to several other directors before finally deciding to direct the film himself.
Principal photography took place in Kraków, Poland, over the course of 72 days in 1993. Spielberg shot the film in black and white and approached it as a documentary. Cinematographer Janusz Kamiński wanted to give the film a sense of timelessness. John Williams composed the score, and violinist Itzhak Perlman performs the film's main theme.
Schindler's List premiered on November 30, 1993, in Washington, D.C. and it was released on December 15, 1993, in the United States. Often listed among the greatest films ever made, it was also a box office success, earning $321.2 million worldwide on a $22 million budget. It was the recipient of seven Academy Awards (out of twelve nominations), including Best Picture, Best Director, Best Adapted Screenplay, and Best Original Score, as well as numerous other awards (including seven BAFTAs and three Golden Globes). In 2007, the American Film Institute ranked the film 8th on its list of the 100 best American films of all time. The Library of Congress selected it for preservation in the National Film Registry in 2004.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schindler%27s_List</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0372784/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Batman Begins</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Crime</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>15 June 2005 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Christopher Nolan</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Batman Begins is a 2005 superhero film based on the DC Comics character Batman, directed by Christopher Nolan and written by Nolan and David S. Goyer. It stars Christian Bale, Michael Caine, Liam Neeson, Katie Holmes, Gary Oldman, Cillian Murphy, Tom Wilkinson, Rutger Hauer, Ken Watanabe, and Morgan Freeman. The film reboots the Batman film series, telling the origin story of Bruce Wayne from the death of his parents to his journey to become Batman and his fight to stop Ra's al Ghul and the Scarecrow from plunging Gotham City into chaos.
After a series of unsuccessful projects to resurrect Batman on screen following the critical failure of Batman &amp; Robin (1997), Nolan and Goyer began work on the film in early 2003. Aiming for a darker, more realistic tone compared to the previous films, a primary goal for their vision was to engage the audience's emotional investment in both the Batman and Bruce Wayne identities of the lead character. The film, which was principally shot in the United Kingdom, Iceland and Chicago, relied heavily on traditional stunts and miniature effects, with computer-generated imagery being used in a minimal capacity compared to other action films. Comic book storylines such as The Man Who Falls, Batman: Year One and Batman: The Long Halloween served as inspiration.
Batman Begins opened on June 15, 2005, in the United States and Canada in 3,858 theaters. It grossed over $48 million in its opening weekend in North America, eventually grossing over $374 million worldwide. The film received highly positive reviews and is considered by many critics to be one of the best superhero films of the 2000s. It was nominated for an Academy Award for Best Cinematography and three BAFTA awards. It was followed by The Dark Knight (2008) and The Dark Knight Rises (2012), which constitute The Dark Knight Trilogy.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Batman_Begins</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1220719/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>O Grande Mestre</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Biography</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>6 February 2009 (Brazil)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Wilson Yip</value>
    </director>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0198781/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Monsters, Inc.</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Comedy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>2 November 2001 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Pete Docter</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Monsters, Inc. is a 2001 American computer-animated comedy film produced by Pixar Animation Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Pictures. Featuring the voices of John Goodman, Billy Crystal, Steve Buscemi, James Coburn, and Jennifer Tilly, the film was directed by Pete Docter in his directorial debut, and executive produced by John Lasseter and Andrew Stanton. The film centers on two monsters employed at the titular energy-producing factory Monsters, Inc. – top scarer James P. &quot;Sulley&quot; Sullivan and his one-eyed partner and best friend Mike Wazowski. In the film, employees at Monsters, Inc. generate their city's power by scaring human children, but they themselves are afraid that the children are toxic to them, and when one child enters the factory, Sulley and Mike must return her home before it is too late.
Docter began developing the film in 1996, and wrote the story with Jill Culton, Jeff Pidgeon, and Ralph Eggleston. Fellow Pixar director Andrew Stanton wrote the screenplay with screenwriter Daniel Gerson. The characters went through many incarnations over the film's five-year production process. The technical team and animators found new ways to render fur and cloth realistically for the film. Randy Newman, who composed the music for Pixar's three prior films, returned to compose its fourth.
Monsters, Inc. was praised by critics and proved to be a major box office success from its release on November 2, 2001, generating over $577 million worldwide and becoming the third highest-grossing film of 2001. Monsters, Inc. saw a 3D re-release in theaters on December 19, 2012. A prequel, Monsters University, directed by Dan Scanlon, was released on June 21, 2013, 12 years after the film's original release.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monsters,_Inc.</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0440963/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Bourne Ultimatum</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Mystery</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>3 August 2007 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Paul Greengrass</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Bourne Ultimatum is a 2007 action thriller film directed by Paul Greengrass loosely based on the novel of the same name by Robert Ludlum.  The screenplay was written by Tony Gilroy, Scott Z. Burns and George Nolfi and based on a screen story of the novel by Gilroy.  The Bourne Ultimatum is the third in the Jason Bourne film series, being preceded by The Bourne Identity (2002) and The Bourne Supremacy (2004). The fourth film, The Bourne Legacy, was released in August 2012, without the involvement of Damon, and the fifth film (a direct sequel to Ultimatum), Jason Bourne, was released in July 2016.
Matt Damon reprises his role as Ludlum's signature character, former CIA assassin and psychogenic amnesiac Jason Bourne. In the film, Bourne continues his search for information about his past before he was part of Operation Treadstone and becomes a target of a similar assassin program.
The Bourne Ultimatum was produced by Universal Pictures and was released on August 3, 2007, and grossed a total of $442 million worldwide becoming, at the time, Damon's highest-grossing film with him as the lead. The film was chosen by National Board of Review as one of the top ten films of 2007 and went on to win all three of its nominations at the 80th Academy Awards: Best Film Editing, Best Sound Mixing and Best Sound Editing.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Bourne_Ultimatum_(film)</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114709/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Toy Story</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Comedy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>22 November 1995 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>John Lasseter</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Toy Story is a 1995 American computer-animated buddy adventure comedy film produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures. The directorial debut of John Lasseter, it was the first feature-length film to be entirely computer-animated, as well as the first feature film from Pixar. Taking place in a world where anthropomorphic toys pretend to be lifeless when humans are present, its plot focuses on the relationship between Woody, an old-fashioned pullstring cowboy doll (voiced by Tom Hanks), and Buzz Lightyear, an astronaut action figure (voiced by Tim Allen), as they evolve from rivals competing for the affections of their owner Andy to friends who work together to be reunited with him as his family prepares to move to a new home. The screenplay was written by Joss Whedon, Andrew Stanton, Joel Cohen, and Alec Sokolow from a story by Lasseter, Pete Docter, Stanton, and Joe Ranft. The film features music by Randy Newman, and was executive-produced by Steve Jobs and Edwin Catmull.
Pixar, which had produced short animated films to promote their computers, was approached by Disney to produce a computer-animated feature film after the success of their short film Tin Toy (1988), which is told from a small toy's perspective. Lasseter, Stanton, and Docter wrote early story treatments which were thrown out by Disney, who wanted the film's tone to be &quot;edgier&quot;. After several disastrous story reels, production was halted and the script was re-written, better reflecting the tone and theme Pixar desired: that &quot;toys deeply want children to play with them, and that this desire drives their hopes, fears, and actions&quot;. The studio, then consisting of a relatively small number of employees, produced the film under minor financial constraints.
Toy Story was released in theaters on November 22, 1995, and was the highest-grossing film on its opening weekend, earning over $373 million at the worldwide box office. It was positively reviewed by critics and audiences, who praised the animation's technical innovation, the wit and thematic sophistication of the screenplay, and the performances of Hanks and Allen; it is considered by many to be one of the best animated films ever made. The film received three Academy Award nominations, including Best Original Screenplay, Best Original Score, and Best Original Song for &quot;You've Got a Friend in Me&quot;, as well as winning a Special Achievement Academy Award. In 2005, it was inducted into the National Film Registry as being &quot;culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant&quot; in its first year of eligibility. In addition to home media and theatrical re-releases, Toy Story-inspired material includes toys, video games, theme park attractions, spin-offs, merchandise, and two sequels — Toy Story 2 (1999) and Toy Story 3 (2010) — both of which also garnered massive commercial success and critical acclaim, with a fourth film titled Toy Story 4 scheduled for release in 2019.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toy_Story</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0947798/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Black Swan</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>17 December 2010 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Darren Aronofsky</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The black swan (Cygnus atratus) is a large waterbird, a species of swan which breeds mainly in the southeast and southwest regions of Australia.  Within Australia they are nomadic, with erratic migration patterns dependent upon climatic conditions. Black swans are large birds with mostly black plumage and red bills. They are monogamous breeders, and are unusual in that one-quarter of all pairings are homosexual, mostly between males. Both partners share incubation and cygnet rearing duties.
Black swans were introduced to various countries as an ornamental bird in the 1800s, but have escaped and formed stable populations. A small population of black swans exists on the River Thames at Marlow, on the Brook running through the small town of Dawlish  in Devon  (they have become the symbol of the town), near the River Itchen, Hampshire, and the River Tees near Stockton on Tees. Described scientifically by English naturalist John Latham in 1790, the black swan was formerly placed into a monotypic genus, Chenopis. Black swans can be found singly, or in loose companies numbering into the hundreds or even thousands. Black swans are popular birds in zoological gardens and bird collections, and escapees are sometimes seen outside their natural range.

</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_swan</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0071853/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Monty Python and the Holy Grail</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Comedy</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>27 June 1975 (Ireland)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Terry Gilliam</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Monty Python and the Holy Grail is a 1975 British slapstick comedy film concerning the Arthurian legend, written and performed by the Monty Python comedy group of Graham Chapman, John Cleese, Terry Gilliam, Eric Idle, Terry Jones and Michael Palin, and directed by Gilliam and Jones.  It was conceived during the hiatus between the third and fourth series of their BBC television series Monty Python's Flying Circus.
In contrast to the group's first film, And Now for Something Completely Different, a compilation of sketches from the first two television series, Holy Grail draws on new material, parodying the legend of King Arthur's quest for the Holy Grail. 30 years later, Idle used the film as the basis for the musical Spamalot.
Monty Python and the Holy Grail grossed more than any British film exhibited in the US in 1975. In the US, it was selected as the second best comedy of all time in the ABC special Best in Film: The Greatest Movies of Our Time. In the UK, readers of Total Film magazine ranked it the fifth greatest comedy film of all time; a similar poll of Channel 4 viewers placed it sixth (2000).</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monty_Python_and_the_Holy_Grail</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0180093/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Requiem for a Dream</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>15 December 2000 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Darren Aronofsky</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Requiem for a Dream is a 2000 American psychological drama film directed by Darren Aronofsky and starring Ellen Burstyn, Jared Leto, Jennifer Connelly, and Marlon Wayans. The film is based on the novel of the same name by Hubert Selby, Jr., with whom Aronofsky wrote the screenplay.
The film depicts four different forms of drug addiction, which lead to the characters' imprisonment in a world of delusion and reckless desperation that is subsequently overtaken by reality, thus leaving them as hollow shells of their former selves.Requiem for a Dream was screened out of competition at the 2000 Cannes Film Festival and received positive reviews from critics upon its U.S. release. Burstyn was nominated for the Academy Award for Best Actress for her performance.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Requiem_for_a_Dream</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0338013/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Romance</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>19 March 2004 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Michel Gondry</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind is a 2004 American science fiction romantic comedy film written by Charlie Kaufman and directed by Michel Gondry. It follows an estranged couple who have erased each other from their memories, then, started dating again. Pierre Bismuth created the story with Kaufman and Gondry. The ensemble cast includes Jim Carrey, Kate Winslet, Kirsten Dunst, Mark Ruffalo, Elijah Wood, and Tom Wilkinson. The title of the film is a quotation from the 1717 poem Eloisa to Abelard by Alexander Pope.
The film uses elements of the psychological thriller and a nonlinear narrative to explore the nature of memory and romantic love. It opened in North America to wide acclaim on March 19, 2004, and grossed over $70 million worldwide. It won the Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay, and Winslet received a nomination for Academy Award for Best Actress. The film developed a cult following in the years after its release and many critics now regard it as one of the greatest films of the 21st century.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eternal_Sunshine_of_the_Spotless_Mind</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1675434/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Intouchables</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Biography</value>
      <value>Comedy</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>31 August 2012 (Brazil)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Olivier Nakache</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Intouchables (French: Intouchables [ɛ̃tuʃabl]), also known as Untouchable (UK), is a 2011 French buddy comedy-drama film  directed by Olivier Nakache &amp; Éric Toledano. It stars François Cluzet and Omar Sy. Nine weeks after its release in France on 2 November 2011, it became the second biggest box office hit in France, just behind the 2008 film Welcome to the Sticks. The film was voted the cultural event of 2011 in France with 52% of votes in a poll by Fnac. The film has received several award nominations. In France, the film won the César Award for Best Actor for Omar Sy, and garnered seven further nominations for the César Awards, including the César Award for Best Film, which it lost to the Best Picture winner The Artist.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Intouchables</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1130884/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Shutter Island</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Mystery</value>
      <value>Thriller</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>19 February 2010 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Martin Scorsese</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Shutter Island is a 2010 American neo-noir psychological thriller film directed by Martin Scorsese and written by Laeta Kalogridis, based on Dennis Lehane's 2003 novel of the same name. Leonardo DiCaprio stars as U.S. Marshal Edward &quot;Teddy&quot; Daniels who is investigating a psychiatric facility on Shutter Island after one of the patients goes missing. Mark Ruffalo plays his partner officer, Ben Kingsley is the facility's lead psychiatrist, and Michelle Williams is Daniels' wife. Released on February 19, 2010, the film received generally favorable reviews from critics, was chosen by National Board of Review as one of the top ten films of 2010 and grossed over $294 million worldwide.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shutter_Island_(film)</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0758758/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Into the Wild</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Biography</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>19 October 2007 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Sean Penn</value>
    </director>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0101414/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Beauty and the Beast</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Family</value>
      <value>Fantasy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>22 November 1991 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Gary Trousdale</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Beauty and the Beast (French: La Belle et la Bête) is a fairy tale written by French novelist Gabrielle-Suzanne Barbot de Villeneuve and published in 1740 in La Jeune Américaine et les contes marins (The Young American and Marine Tales). Her lengthy version was abridged, rewritten, and published first by Jeanne-Marie Leprince de Beaumont in 1756 in Magasin des enfants (Children's Collection) and by Andrew Lang in the Blue Fairy Book of his Fairy Book series in 1889, to produce the version(s) most commonly retold. It was influenced by some earlier stories, such as &quot;Cupid and Psyche&quot;, The Golden Ass written by  Lucius Apuleius Madaurensis in the 2nd century AD, and &quot;The Pig King&quot;, an Italian fairytale published by Giovanni Francesco Straparola in The Facetious Nights of Straparola.Variants of the tale are known across Europe. In France, for example, Zémire and Azor is an operatic version of the story, written by Marmontel and composed by Grétry in 1771, which had enormous success well into the 19th century; it is based on the second version of the tale. Amour pour amour (Love for love), by Nivelle de la Chaussée, is a 1742 play based on de Villeneuve's version. According to researchers at universities in Durham and Lisbon, the story originated around 4,000 years ago.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beauty_and_the_Beast</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0034583/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Casablanca</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Romance</value>
      <value>War</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>23 January 1943 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Michael Curtiz</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Casablanca (Arabic: الدار البيضاء‎, translit. ad-dār al-bayḍāʾ; Berber languages: ⴰⵏⴼⴰ, translit. anfa; local informal name: Kaẓa), located in the central-western part of Morocco bordering the Atlantic Ocean, is the largest city in Morocco. It is also the largest city in the Maghreb, as well as one of the largest and most important cities in Africa, both economically and demographically.
Casablanca is Morocco's chief port and one of the largest financial centers on the continent. According to the 2014 population estimate, the city has a population of about 3.35 million in the urban area and over 6.8 million in the Casablanca-Settat region. Casablanca is considered the economic and business center of Morocco, although the national political capital is Rabat.
The leading Moroccan companies and international corporations doing business in the country have their headquarters and main industrial facilities in Casablanca. Recent industrial statistics show Casablanca retains its historical position as the main industrial zone of the country. The Port of Casablanca is one of the largest artificial ports in the world, and the second largest port of North Africa, after Tanger-Med 40 km (25 mi) east of Tangier. Casablanca also hosts the primary naval base for the Royal Moroccan Navy.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casablanca</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120382/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Truman Show</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Comedy</value>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>5 June 1998 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Peter Weir</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Truman Show is a 1998 American satirical science fiction film directed by Peter Weir, produced by Scott Rudin, Andrew Niccol, Edward S. Feldman, and Adam Schroeder, and written by Niccol. The film stars Jim Carrey as Truman Burbank, adopted and raised by a corporation inside a simulated television show revolving around his life, until he discovers it and decides to escape.  Additional roles are performed by Laura Linney, Noah Emmerich, Natascha McElhone, Holland Taylor, Ed Harris, and Brian Delate.
The Truman Show was originally a spec script by Niccol, inspired by an episode of The Twilight Zone called &quot;Special Service&quot;. Unlike the finished product, it was more of a science-fiction thriller, with the story set in New York City. Scott Rudin purchased the script, and set up production at Paramount Pictures. Brian De Palma was to direct before Weir signed as director, making the film for $60 million—$20 million less than the original estimate. Niccol rewrote the script while the crew was waiting for Carrey to sign. The majority of filming took place at Seaside, Florida, a master-planned community located in the Florida Panhandle.
The film was a financial success, debuting to critical acclaim, and earned numerous nominations at the 71st Academy Awards, 56th Golden Globe Awards, 52nd British Academy Film Awards and The Saturn Awards. The Truman Show has been analyzed as a thesis on Christianity, metaphilosophy, simulated reality, existentialism and reality television.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Truman_Show</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1049413/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Up</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Animation</value>
      <value>Adventure</value>
      <value>Comedy</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>29 May 2009 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Pete Docter</value>
    </director>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0050986/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Wild Strawberries</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>Romance</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>22 June 1959 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Ingmar Bergman</value>
    </director>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0088247/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>The Terminator</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Action</value>
      <value>Sci-Fi</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>26 October 1984 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>James Cameron</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>The Terminator is a 1984 American science-fiction action horror film directed by James Cameron. It stars Arnold Schwarzenegger as the Terminator, a cyborg assassin sent back in time from 2029 to 1984 to kill Sarah Connor (Linda Hamilton), whose son will one day become a savior against machines in a post-apocalyptic future. Michael Biehn plays Kyle Reese, a soldier from the future sent back in time to protect Connor. The screenplay is credited to Cameron and producer Gale Anne Hurd, while co-writer William Wisher Jr. received a credit for additional dialogue. Executive producers John Daly and Derek Gibson of Hemdale Film Corporation were instrumental in the film's financing and production.The Terminator topped the US box office for two weeks and helped launch Cameron's film career and solidify Schwarzenegger's. It received critical acclaim, with many praising its pacing, action scenes and Schwarzenegger's performance. Its success led to a franchise consisting of four sequels (Terminator 2: Judgment Day, Terminator 3: Rise of the Machines, Terminator Salvation and Terminator Genisys), a television series, comic books, novels and video games. In 2008, The Terminator was selected by the Library of Congress for preservation in the National Film Registry, being deemed &quot;culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant&quot;.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Terminator</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
  <movie>
    <uri>
      <value>http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0078788/</value>
    </uri>
    <name>
      <value>Apocalypse Now</value>
    </name>
    <genre>
      <value>Drama</value>
      <value>War</value>
    </genre>
    <release>
      <value>15 August 1979 (USA)</value>
    </release>
    <director>
      <value>Francis Ford Coppola</value>
    </director>
    <info>
      <value>Apocalypse Now is a 1979 American epic war film directed, produced, and co-written by Francis Ford Coppola. It stars Marlon Brando, Robert Duvall, Martin Sheen, Frederic Forrest, Albert Hall, Sam Bottoms, Laurence Fishburne, and Dennis Hopper. The screenplay, co-written by Coppola and John Milius (who received an Oscar nomination for Best Adapted Screenplay) and featuring narration written by Michael Herr, is an updating of Joseph Conrad's novella Heart of Darkness. The setting was changed from late nineteenth-century Congo to the Vietnam War ca. 1969–70, the years in which Green Beret Colonel Robert Rheault, commander of the 5th Special Forces Group, was indicted for murder and President Richard Nixon authorized the secret Cambodian Campaign. Coppola said that Rheault was an inspiration for the character of Colonel Kurtz. The voice-over narration of Willard was written by war correspondent Herr, whose 1977 Vietnam memoir Dispatches brought him to the attention of Coppola. A major influence on the film was Werner Herzog's Aguirre, the Wrath of God (1972), which also features a river journey and an insane soldier. The film revolves around a river journey from South Vietnam into Cambodia undertaken by Captain Benjamin L. Willard (a character based on Conrad's Marlow and played by Sheen), who is on a secret mission to assassinate Colonel Kurtz, a renegade Army officer accused of murder who is presumed insane.
The film has been noted for the problems encountered while making it, chronicled in the documentary Hearts of Darkness: A Filmmaker's Apocalypse (1991). These problems included Brando arriving on the set overweight and completely unprepared, expensive sets being destroyed by severe weather, and Sheen having a breakdown and suffering a near-fatal heart attack while on location. Problems continued after production as the release was postponed several times while Coppola edited thousands of feet of film.
Apocalypse Now was honored with the Palme d'Or at Cannes Film Festival, nominated for the Academy Award for Best Picture, and the Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture – Drama. Initial reviews were mixed; while Vittorio Storaro's cinematography was widely acclaimed, several critics found Coppola's handling of the story's major themes to be anticlimactic and intellectually disappointing. Reevaluated in subsequent years, Apocalypse Now is today considered to be one of the greatest films ever made. It ranked No. 14 in Sight &amp; Sound's greatest films poll in 2012. In 2000, the film was selected for preservation in the National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being &quot;culturally, historically or aesthetically significant&quot;.</value>
    </info>
    <more_info>
      <value>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apocalypse_Now</value>
    </more_info>
  </movie>
</Movies>
